<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://www.rssboard.org/media-rss">
  <channel>
    <title>GoHobo | Curated Alternative Travel Resources | Adventures for Everyone.</title>
    <description>GoHobo is a mindset, a mentality, &amp; a tribe. Curated alternative travel resources and inspiration for travellers, adventurers, digital nomads, vandwellers &amp; explorers. 
</description>
    <link>https://gohobo.co//</link>
    <atom:link href="https://gohobo.co/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 20:12:56 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 20:12:56 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Budget-friendly Travel Planning Made Easy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re a single traveller or like trekking and backpacking in groups, you will need to plan ahead to make sure your budget goes as far as you want to go. From saving money on air travel to taking advantage of offers and discounts, there are several ways to make the most out of your budget. Below you will find a few tips on planning your ultimate vacation while making sure you don’t overspend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;take-the-road-less-travelled&quot;&gt;Take the Road Less Travelled&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Popular destinations have great hotels, but you will have to cope with higher prices and greater crowds. The good news is that there are several stunning places to be discovered, and - if you do your research right - you can hike up some of the best mountains for less than you would pay for a package holiday. Check out some of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.independent.co.uk/travel/19-of-the-most-incredible-and-affordable-undiscovered-holiday-destinations-in-europe-a7807201.html&quot; title=&quot;independent.co.uk/travel&quot;&gt;latest holiday gems&lt;/a&gt;, such as Brest in Belarus, or Sheki in Azerbaijan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;low-season-offers&quot;&gt;Low Season Offers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless you are going on a beach holiday, you don’t need sunshine all day. Whether you would like to discover one of the historic sites or visit a mountain range, you can travel low season. Check out the monthly comparison of flight ticket prices online, and choose to travel when others are busy working or taking kids to school. Avoid the summer months, and find locations with great weather during the winter when people are usually staying at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;set-up-a-base&quot;&gt;Set Up a Base&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/budget-friendly-travel-made-easy/blue-vw-van.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;VW Bus by Ben Shanks&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@benshanks&quot;&gt;Image credit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is that you can book your accommodation cheap anywhere in the country and hire a car to get around. If you have a list of sites you would like to visit in El Salvador, it might be cheaper to book a room at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marriott.com/hotels/travel/salcy-courtyard-san-salvador&quot; title=&quot;marriot.com&quot;&gt;Courtyard San Salvador&lt;/a&gt; and go on group tours or hire a car to check out all the historic and natural sites you want to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hire-local-guides&quot;&gt;Hire Local Guides&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of booking your tours with a local travel agent when &lt;a href=&quot;https://gohobo.co/journal/travelling-around-the-world-options/&quot; title=&quot;GoHobo.co&quot;&gt;visiting another continent&lt;/a&gt;, you might want to talk to agents directly. Search for small private, family-run businesses, and support people in the community, instead of paying high commissions for agents. If you are planning on visiting India, find a &lt;a href=&quot;http://merrygotravels.in/&quot; title=&quot;merrygotravels.in&quot;&gt;local tour operator in North India&lt;/a&gt; who will give you a better price than you would get with UK companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;make-friends&quot;&gt;Make Friends&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/budget-friendly-travel-made-easy/jogging-man-algeria.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Man jogging in Algeria&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@hoovr01&quot;&gt;Image credit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great way to save on travel is making friends abroad before you travel and after. You’ll be surprised how helpful locals can be, and how happy they are to show you around the best places not many tourists know about. You might decide to book an AirBnB or similar type of accommodation, learn a few words in the local language, and get personalised recommendations from locals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you are travelling with friends or alone, making the most out of low season offers is a great idea. Search for places that are not yet popular among the crowds of tourists, and do your research. Use local companies and learn a few words in the local language, so you can get the real feel of the culture.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <media:content url="https://gohobo.co/assets/img/blog/budget-friendly-travel-made-easy/budget-travel-woman-walking.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpg" > </media:content>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://gohobo.co/journal/budget-friendly-travel-planning-made-easy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gohobo.co/journal/budget-friendly-travel-planning-made-easy/</guid>
        
        <category>contributed</category>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        
        <category>journal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Travelling Around The World: Your Options</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re seriously considering travelling around the world, there are many ways that you can do so, whether you decide to go with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/geoffreymorrison/2016/07/31/10-tips-for-travelling-with-friends/#7e9db35d5e60&quot; title=&quot;Forbes.com - Travelling with friends&quot;&gt;group of your friends&lt;/a&gt;, or even just on your own. But before you jet off on your adventures, you need to think about how you’re going to pull this off. There are plenty of different options out there, but here are two of the most common options you have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;backpacking-as-a-solo-traveller&quot;&gt;Backpacking: As a solo traveller&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people decide to go backpacking because they think that it’s the cheapest option, but one thing you need to know is that most people that set off this way already have a large sum of money that they have been saving up. Just because they aren’t staying in the luxury hotels doesn’t mean they don’t need a lot of money. They are still having to pay for transport to get them from A to B, they are still having to pay for accommodation to make sure they have somewhere safe to sleep at night, and they are still having to pay for food and drink. So bare this in mind. Anyone that decides to start travelling needs to have saved up a decent amount of money - even just for the emergency fund in case things don’t go to plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have a lot of savings then you may be thinking ‘I need to look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://personalloan.co/personal-loans-near-me/&quot; title=&quot;PersonalLoan.co - Loans near me&quot;&gt;loans near me&lt;/a&gt;’, and you could be right. You can get one of these from your bank or the credit union, so get looking around in your area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;campervan-as-a-pair-or-a-larger-group&quot;&gt;Campervan: As a pair or a larger group&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being your own means of transport is a good idea if you like to explore and have the freedom to go anywhere you want - like backpacking, minus having to rely on other people to get you around. Driving means you can pull over when you wish, take a break, have a nap, and you’re safe &lt;a href=&quot;https://gohobo.co/journal/why-you-should-live-and-travel-in-a-van-p1/&quot; title=&quot;GoHobo.co - Why you should live and travel in a van&quot;&gt;inside your own vehicle&lt;/a&gt;. Plus this cuts costs down because you aren’t having to rely on paying for accommodation because you already have it with you. This is also beneficial because essentially you have a place to put things and keep them stored away without having to worry about it not being secure, whereas if you were backpacking, for example, there’s only so much you can take with you from the lack of space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you decide to go with someone else or a whole group, this will end up cheaper as everyone can chip in to pay for fuel. When travelling in a group, you can put your money in together and have one pot for food and drink and one pot for fuel, as well as each person’s own personal spending money. That way there’s no discussion needed every time something needs to be bought because you’ve all put the same amount of money in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of what decision you make, the most important thing is that you have enough money, and you keep yourself safe. Don’t do anything that doesn’t feel right - it’s just not worth the risk. And also, have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <media:content url="https://gohobo.co/assets/img/blog/travelling-around-the-world/airplane.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpg" > </media:content>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://gohobo.co/journal/travelling-around-the-world-options/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gohobo.co/journal/travelling-around-the-world-options/</guid>
        
        <category>contributed</category>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        
        <category>journal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Spending A Day At Moreton Bay</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Brisbane is without a doubt one of the unsung gems of Queensland and one of the most captivating cities in all of Australia. There are few cities anywhere in the world where you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://koala.net/en-au/&quot; title=&quot;Koala.net&quot;&gt;pet koalas&lt;/a&gt;, see an operatic production in an underground theatre that used to be a reservoir, sun yourself on a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.visitbrisbane.com.au/south-bank/things-to-do/swimming-at-south-bank?sc_lang=en-au&quot; title=&quot;visitBrisbane.com.au&quot;&gt;man-made beach&lt;/a&gt; and climb to a peak 300m above sea level all in one day. There’s so much to see and do in Brisbane that it can be daunting for newcomers. That’s why we’re using laser focus in this post, here we’ll focus entirely on the things to see and do around the Moreton Bay region. However much time you have to spare and whatever your budget there’s plenty to do in this charming and picturesque area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;charter-a-boat&quot;&gt;Charter a Boat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like so many of Australia’s coastal cities, Brisbane is as exciting to experience on the water as on the land. Although there are many marine life tours as well as organised snorkelling and diving expeditions, many people prefer the freedom of exploring the open waters at their own pace. If this sounds like your perfect way to start a day it’s easy and affordable to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sailfree.com.au/cms/charter-boats-brisbane/&quot; title=&quot;SailFree.com.au&quot;&gt;charter boats&lt;/a&gt; from Moreton Bay. You can enjoy a barbecue on deck, snorkel and swim at your leisure or sail along the beautiful Brisbane river for a whale’s eye view of the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;speaking-of-whales&quot;&gt;Speaking of whales…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you get a glowy feeling from seeing marine life in their natural habitat (who doesn’t?) you can witness these majestic underwater mammals doing their thing from June through to October from the bay. Departing from Radcliffe Jetty Brisbane Whale Watching offers fun and informative tours that cruise the bay for hours to give whale fans their fix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;explore-the-redcliffe-botanic-gardens&quot;&gt;Explore the Redcliffe Botanic Gardens&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Australia is home to some of the most beautiful and fascinating arboreal life in the world so why not take a little time to enjoy it up close and personal. Even the most overworked mind can find peace and tranquility walking among this haven for indigenous plant life (which used to be a cow paddock). There’s plenty to do for the kids as well including a herb garden and a floral sensory experience. Finish your trip with a look around the Redcliffe Art Gallery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;swim-and-relax-in-settlement-cove&quot;&gt;Swim and relax in Settlement Cove&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who says you have to spend a fortune to have a fun and relaxing day? The best things in life are free and so is a splash around the picturesque Settlement Cove which offers a resort quality swim at no cost whatsoever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;watch-the-sun-set-over-the-glasshouse-mountains&quot;&gt;Watch the sun set over the Glasshouse Mountains&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nature lovers will find unmatched tranquil beauty among the channel of &lt;a href=&quot;http://visitbribieisland.com.au/bribie-island/explore/pumicestone-passage/&quot;&gt;Pumicestone Passage&lt;/a&gt;. Between Bribie island and the Caboolture coast this channel is a protected safe haven for indigenous birds animals and marine life. Here you can enjoy a range of watersports or just relax amongst the breathtaking views with an astonishing view of the Glasshouse Mountains which offer a wonderful view of the setting sun.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <media:content url="https://gohobo.co/assets/img/blog/moreton-bay/giant-fig-tree.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpg" > </media:content>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://gohobo.co/journal/spending-the-day-at-moreton-bay/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gohobo.co/journal/spending-the-day-at-moreton-bay/</guid>
        
        <category>australia</category>
        
        <category>tourism</category>
        
        
        <category>journal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Perfect Peru - Unmissable Adventures In The Andes And Beyond</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Peru is widely accepted as the very heart of ancient civilisations, yet there is much more to Peru than this. The country has a fascinating mix of the icy mountain peaks of the Andes - which have always offered a natural draw for trekkers and climbers alike - to the desert coast, perfect for surfing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who prefer a jungle adventure, the Amazon Basin is well known for its exceptional biodiversity and dangerous rainforest terrain. Parque Nacional Manu oversees one of its most untouched and inaccessible areas. Located at the mouth of one of the many feeder rivers leading to the Amazon River itself, Rio Manu, this entanglement is a literal hotbed for native wildlife. You could see tapirs in their natural environment, even masses of macaws. A breathtaking and awe-inspiring spot for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gohobo.co/journal/health-benefits-of-connecting-with-nature/&quot; title=&quot;GoHobo.co - Health Benefits of Connecting with Nature&quot;&gt;nature lover&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tempted-by-lake-titicaca&quot;&gt;Tempted By Lake Titicaca&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ancient scriptures believe this lake to be the birthplace of the sun itself. Once you look at the crystal azure waters, you can see where this belief was born. It’s honestly a magical encounter, one best experienced by spending the night on one of the lake’s islands. Once you have seen the sunset surrounded by the shimmering waters of the lake, it is a memory that will stay with you forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-the-trail-we-blaze&quot;&gt;On the trail, we blaze…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deep from the depths of the Urubamba Valley, an ancient stairway appears atop the clouds. As if from a fairy story this footpath runs alongside the ruins of waypoints long forgotten, and was the principal entry point to the beautiful estate of Machu Picchu for the Incas. It has become a pilgrimage of a sort, for the thousands of visitors who brave the trail each year. This incredible and important archaeological site is reached only after a touch and sometimes rugged four-day trek through magnificent scenery to the most spectacular and world-renowned place of interest. Guided &lt;a href=&quot;http://ikreatepassions.com/2017/11/10/the-ultimate-checklist-to-get-more-from-your-first-hiking-holiday/&quot; title=&quot;I Kreate Passions.com&quot;&gt;Machu Picchu hikes&lt;/a&gt; are recommended to take in what you see in all its glory completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;drawing-a-blanca&quot;&gt;Drawing A Blanca&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Cordillera Blanca is a grand mountain range seated at the very core of Peru. Just taking in the magnificent views can make even the most sedentary of us want to explore its craggy peaks, each covered in dabs of bright white snow. It may not only be the altitude that takes your breath away when you behold the vista before you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;its-ruined&quot;&gt;It’s ruined&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Andes are spotted all over with the traces of ancient towns and cities. A walled stronghold built by the Chachapoyas people, Kuelap stands among the most majestic, perched upon a mountain in the northern Peruvian cloud forest. The aspects of the Utcubamba Valley are unbelievable, the ruins just amazing, even the journey forged through timeless rustic hamlets is exceptional and unforgettable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;glyph-tastic&quot;&gt;Glyph-tastic!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of Planet Earth’s most massive enigmas, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nationalgeographic.com/archaeology-and-history/archaeology/nasca-lines/&quot; title=&quot;National Geographic - Nasca Lines&quot;&gt;The Nazca Lines&lt;/a&gt;, can be found by exploring the Peruvian coast.  Made up of over 70 ancient glyphs of animals and other configurations, they are so vast you can only truly take them in by taking to the air. That is where the puzzle lies. Why design something only really appreciated by flying over them, something well out of the remit of man when they were drawn. Their purpose is unclear, unknown, yet for a truly out of this world experience, soar over them in one of the many light aircraft experiences available and get a real sense of designs that have a higher purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <media:content url="https://gohobo.co/assets/img/blog/perfect-peru/perfect-peru.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpg" > </media:content>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://gohobo.co/journal/perfect-peru/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gohobo.co/journal/perfect-peru/</guid>
        
        <category>peru</category>
        
        <category>adventure</category>
        
        
        <category>journal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Travelling on the Orient Express</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the age of modern high-speed transport, it is easy to forget what travelling by train used to be like. In previous generations, a train journey was considered a luxury and adventure. While there are many famous train journeys across the globe (most are still operational today), none hold the same esteem and legend as the Orient Express.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea for the Orient Express came from a Belgian called Georges Nagelmackers, who was inspired by America’s vast rail network. He planned to create a similar service that stretched across Europe. The famous train departed for its first official journey from Paris to Vienna in 1883. The Orient Express was compared to Europe’s finest hotels and became one of the main modes of transport for royalty. The full journey from Paris to Istanbul was an 80-hour trip. Since that inaugural trip the train and routes have changed, and in 1962 the original service was stopped and replaced with a service called the Direct Orient Express. Today the service is owned by Belmod, and travellers can continue to get a taste of the original Orient Express (now called the Venice Simplon-Orient-Express (VSOE)).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/travelling-the-orient-express/orient-express-poster.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://people.com/home/we-tried-it-a-ride-on-the-real-life-orient-express/&quot; title=&quot;People.com&quot;&gt;People Magazine editor Samantha Miller reveals that her ride&lt;/a&gt; on the VSOE was every bit memorable: “If you’re a travel buff up for a splurge, riding the Venice Simplon-Orient Express is a whole lot more memorable than a first-class airline trip. Travelling in a work of art is a once-in-a-lifetime experience, but it doesn’t come cheap.” Miller noted that every part of the train projects luxury and style. From the “perfectly designed” sleeping cabins, to the “sleek and scenic” staff. In the famous dining cart she compared the food to “a fancy hotel restaurant”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;art--video&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/rpkUjw3hZgw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons that the Orient Express continues to be popular to this day (the majority of the trips for this year are already sold out) is its role in popular culture. The train has been featured in literature, film, music and games. Agatha Christie’s 1934 novel &lt;em&gt;Murder on the Orient Express&lt;/em&gt; is the most famous story to feature the train. The book captured the imagination of the public, and added to the mystery and mystique around the famed train. This aura of mystique around the Orient Express can be found in nearly every form of media. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slingo.com/slots/orient-express&quot; title=&quot;slingo.com&quot;&gt;The Slingo slot game Orient Express&lt;/a&gt; embraces the wealth and glamour that was described in Christie’s novel, and the game’s design will be instantly recognisable to fans of both the train and book. The latest adaption of &lt;em&gt;Murder on the Orient Express&lt;/em&gt; was the 2017 Kenneth Branagh film that featured an all-star cast including Johnny Depp, Penélope Cruz, and Judi Dench.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;art--video&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/e_jSjlFSEkg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film sparked a renewed interest in the famous train. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.travelandleisure.com/trip-ideas/bus-train/venice-simplon-orient-express&quot; title=&quot;TravelAndLeisure.com&quot;&gt;Travel and Leisure describe how the present day service&lt;/a&gt; continues to honour the train’s illustrious history. Passengers still dress in a black tie for evening cocktails, and it is expected for guests to mingle rather than be confined to their quarters. It is clear that even after all this time, the Orient Express continues to be the world’s most famous train journey.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <media:content url="https://gohobo.co/assets/img/blog/travelling-the-orient-express/orient-express.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpg" > </media:content>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://gohobo.co/journal/travelling-the-orient-express/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gohobo.co/journal/travelling-the-orient-express/</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>promoted</category>
        
        
        <category>journal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Southeast Asia is Still a Backpacker's Paradise</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For backpackers of all shapes and sizes, Southeast Asia continues to capture their imagination. Sure, Europe and South America are still popular choices, but there is something that keeps drawing people back to countries like Vietnam, Cambodia, Thailand, Malaysia, and Indonesia. To find out just why this is, we are going to talk in more detail about what it is that attracts people to this corner of the world. Of course, everyone’s individual reasons are specific, but there are some which keep coming up time and time again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ease-of-travel&quot;&gt;Ease of Travel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For first time travellers, it can be daunting to think about the ways that you are going to get from A to B in a foreign land. However, since so many people come to Southeast Asia, transportation options have opened up all over the place. Of course, the road and rail links are never going to be the same as somewhere like Europe, but this is part of the appeal of travelling to Asia in the first place. Not only is travel easy, it is also very cheap regardless of whether you choose to travel by road, rail or air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fine-food&quot;&gt;Fine Food&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each country you visit has its own culinary traditions, and you are truly blessed by choice in this part of the world. Of course, there are plenty of fine restaurants to choose from, but you are also just as likely to enjoy a fantastic meal at one of the many streetside establishments. One of the great joys of food in Southeast Asia is just how colourful and flavourful it is. When you are out here, make sure that you try as many different options as you can to get a full picture of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;affordability&quot;&gt;Affordability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many backpackers travel with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goatsontheroad.com/how-much-will-south-east-asia-cost/&quot; title=&quot;Goats on the road.com&quot;&gt;strict budget&lt;/a&gt; in mind that they want to stretch out as much as possible. Thankfully, Southeast Asia is the kind of place that you can budget a few dollars a day and still enjoy a great standard of travelling. This means that you can take a much longer trip than you would otherwise be able to in different parts of the world. However, you still need to be on your toes as some people will try to take advantage of your financial naivety by overcharging you for things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stunning-scenery&quot;&gt;Stunning Scenery&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/southeast-asia-backpacker-paradise/southeast-asia-scenery-boats.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Boats in Halong Bay, Vietnam&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pexels.com/photo/vietnam-halong-bay-58597/&quot;&gt;Image credit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether is it is the rising karst cliffs in Vietnam’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lonelyplanet.com/vietnam/northeast-vietnam/halong-bay&quot; title=&quot;LonelyPlanet.com/vietnam&quot;&gt;Halong Bay&lt;/a&gt; or idyllic sandy beaches on one of the Thai islands, Southeast Asia is home to some spectacular scenery every way you turn. The year-round warm weather means that you are able to enjoy the landscapes whenever you choose to pay a visit to this part of the world. For maximum pleasure, go when it is winter back home and you can truly appreciate how far away you are from the cold weather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;major-cities&quot;&gt;Major Cities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are more of a city-dweller, Southeast Asia is home to some of the most fast-paced and electric metropolises in the world. Just some of them include Bangkok, Ho Chi Minh City and Kuala Lumpur. Within these places, you will see eastern and western traditions combined in a way unlike anywhere else. Just around the corner from a street of towering skyscrapers, you will find ancient and peaceful temples. The contrast of the modern and the traditional is something else you will notice about many Southeast Asian cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;expat-community&quot;&gt;Expat Community&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whichever country you visit, you will find an expat community who have fallen in love with the Asian lifestyle and have chosen to make this continent their home. If you can get in touch with locals, they will be able to show you an entirely different side of the country. The affordability of the lifestyle and accommodation in places like &lt;a href=&quot;https://rumahdijual.com/cirebon/&quot;&gt;https://rumahdijual.com/cirebon/&lt;/a&gt; make it more than possible to start a new life here. Who knows, you may even get drawn in yourself!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;long-history&quot;&gt;Long History&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/southeast-asia-backpacker-paradise/southeast-asia-ancient-ruins.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ancient Architecture, Southeast Asia&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pexels.com/u/freeimages9/&quot;&gt;Image credit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of ancient societies began in Southeast Asia, and many remnants from the past are a testament to this. The most obvious example is the dazzling temple of Angkor Wat and the surrounding monuments which make up this huge protected zone. Of course, much of the region went through a much more troubled modern &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dVITTpIiXyE&quot; title=&quot;YouTube.com - The History of Southeast Asia: Every Year&quot;&gt;history&lt;/a&gt;, and there are plenty of reminders of events like the Vietnam War, the destructive and brutal rule of the Khmer Rouge in Cambodia, and the extreme bombing of Laos. In countries like Burma, the political situation still remains very unstable and volatile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cultural-contrasts&quot;&gt;Cultural Contrasts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another major reason why western backpackers like to travel to Southeast Asia is just how different the culture is. You are highly unlikely to be so amazed if you simply travel to Europe or &lt;a href=&quot;https://gohobo.co/journal/awesome-australia-6-best-cities/&quot;&gt;Australia&lt;/a&gt;, though both destinations obviously have their appealing factors as well. Within the region, there are a variety of different cultures existing side by side, all offering their own traditions, languages, fashions and customs. Even as modern life continues to sweep through the region at a rapid pace, a lot of the population are still passionate about upholding their historical rituals and practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;premier-partying&quot;&gt;Premier Partying&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many young backpackers in particular, the opportunity to enjoy the nightlife is one of the main draws of going backpacking in this area. The majority of the cities in the region will offer plenty of bars and clubs which are specifically geared towards young people. The Thai islands are particularly popular destinations, and most people put going to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tripadvisor.ca/Attraction_Review-g303907-d4020022-Reviews-Full_Moon_Party-Ko_Pha_Ngan_Surat_Thani_Province.html&quot; title=&quot;Tripadvisor.ca - Full Moon Party&quot;&gt;Full Moon Party&lt;/a&gt; high up on their list of must-do activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;simple-solitude&quot;&gt;Simple Solitude&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are the kind of person who isn’t that keen on wild parties full of people, there are plenty of places where you can enjoy a more solitary travelling experience. Essentially, you want to look which destinations are on the main backpacker’s trail and head off in the opposite direction. For example, there are plenty of [hill tribes](https://www.wheresidewalksend.com/thai-hill-tribes-debate “WhereSidewalksEnd - Thai Hill Tribes”/) up in the north of Thailand which have not had a great deal of contact with the outside world. Though travelling around this area may be more challenging, it will be worth it to escape the crowds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;friendly-people&quot;&gt;Friendly People&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/southeast-asia-backpacker-paradise/southeast-asia-people-cooking.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Friendly People Grilling, Southeast Asia&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pexels.com/u/amy-chandra-248966/&quot;&gt;Image credit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most noticeable aspects of visiting any part of the world is the type of people who call this area home. Even though many of these people have gone through unimaginable hardships in their lives, you may well be surprised by just how many smiling, open, and happy people you encounter. There is a general sense of optimism and openness which pervades this area. Make sure that you really take the time to speak to the people here to get the best understanding of the region that you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rapid-change&quot;&gt;Rapid Change&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, the whole world is changing at an extremely rapid rate, but the speed of change seems to be especially noticeable in Asia. The population boom, advancement in technology and foreign influence have all hit at a similar time, and it is difficult to say where things are heading next. Visit Southeast Asia now and you are bound to see a completely different place in a few years time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, these are just a few of the reasons why Southeast Asia continues to have that enduring sense of popularity and appeal amongst all kinds of backpackers. There are plenty more draws that bring people to this area, but the affordability, ease of transport, stunning scenery, glorious weather, and friendly people are all high on most people’s list.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <media:content url="https://gohobo.co/assets/img/blog/southeast-asia-backpacker-paradise/southeast-asia-motorbike.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpg" > </media:content>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://gohobo.co/journal/southeast-asia-is-still-backpackers-paradise/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gohobo.co/journal/southeast-asia-is-still-backpackers-paradise/</guid>
        
        <category>southeast asia</category>
        
        <category>backpacking</category>
        
        
        <category>journal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tips for an Incredible Couchsurfing Experience</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A new trend of local accommodation has sparked amongst budget-travelers called couchsurfing. No, it does not mean riding on a couch down a mountain, but simply staying on a stranger’s couch, at their home, for free. The whole concept originally just meant crashing at a friend’s house for a couple nights. Now, it is commonly known as the social media network that has over 12 million users that network throughout 200,000 cities. It may not appeal to everyone, but it is merely a new way to meet locals and make new friends.
Here are some tips on how to have an incredible &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.couchsurfing.com/&quot; title=&quot;Couchsurfing.com&quot;&gt;Couchsurfing&lt;/a&gt; experience on your next trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-your-research&quot;&gt;Do Your Research&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With so many options and so many hosts, the options of where to stay can be exhaustive. Look for people with like interests, and those who you may feel you will connect well with. If your host responds to your request, try looking them up on Facebook, just to make sure that they are legitimate. It is very important to be safe when considering a place to stay. Know exactly where you will be staying and always trust your gut feeling. When looking through their profile, make sure that you read your host’s profile thoroughly. This can help you be more sensitive during your stay. Are your hosts vegetarian? Are they cleanly? Do they have pets? All these could help you determine whether or not you should stay at a certain place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduce-yourself&quot;&gt;Introduce Yourself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First impressions are important, right? In this case, it could really be the make or break of your Couchsurfing experience. Introducing yourself thoroughly is important as it will help your host decide why they should or shouldn’t host you. Think of it like Airbnb; there are &lt;em&gt;hosts&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;guests&lt;/em&gt;, or in this case, &lt;em&gt;couchsurfers&lt;/em&gt;. In order to confirm your spot at your host’s house, send them a message to introduce yourself and politely ask to stay on your visit. Make sure you give as much advance notice to your hosts as possible. If they are available, then you should have no problem staying at all! Writing a personal email is always nicer—and more professional. The more personal you are in an email, the more likely you are to win your host over. Also, the more references on your profile that you have, the more likely you are to be accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;show-your-appreciation&quot;&gt;Show Your Appreciation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cool thing about Couchsurfing is it’s free - the hosts cannot charge. However, there is nothing nicer than receiving a gift when doing something nice for someone. So why not bless your host with one? This could be anything from something from your hometown or a gift card to a restaurant in their area. As an act of kindness, this is a good way to thank your host for opening their home to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/tips-for-an-incredible-couchsurfing-experience/3-show-appreciation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Giving a Gift - Photo by Ben White&quot; title=&quot;Giving a Gift - Photo by Ben White&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@benwhitephotography&quot;&gt;Image source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-golden-rule&quot;&gt;The Golden Rule&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all know this one: “Treat others as you’d like to be treated.” If you had someone come and stay in your home at no charge, and they used things like food or toiletries, you would expect them to replace it. Therefore, you should do the same. If you offer reimbursement, the host will probably decline, but it’s at least nice to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;not-a-dating-site&quot;&gt;NOT a Dating Site&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s just get this out of the way now: this is NOT a dating website. This is not Tinder. Couchsurfing was never intended for such habits or practices. It is recommended that if you are a male, reach out to males or couple hosts only, as things could get messy if you’re not smart. Just be wise and balance your options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cherish-the-relationship&quot;&gt;Cherish the Relationship&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole point of couchsurfing was for one individual to be able to go to another’s home and crash, but it’s developed into something better. Now, the philosophy is to bring people together and to expand worldviews and the travel picture. An important aspect of this is developing friendships, so treating your host as you would your own friend could make all the difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be cleanly. Clean up after yourself. Ask what you can do around the house. Ask if you can cook your host’s dinner. Offer to clean the home. Offer your host to come visit your house. After all, to be a friend, you must show yourself friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/tips-for-an-incredible-couchsurfing-experience/6-cherish-relationship.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sharing Tomatoes - Elaine Casap&quot; title=&quot;Sharing Tomatoes - Elaine Casap&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ecasap.com/?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=gohobo&quot;&gt;Image source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;words-of-wisdom&quot;&gt;Words of Wisdom&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re new to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gohobo.co/adventure-directory/#couchsurfing&quot; title=&quot;Couchsurfing in the GoHobo Adventure Directory&quot;&gt;Couchsurfing&lt;/a&gt; thing, try looking for an experienced host. You certainly want your first experience to be a good one, so pick a Couchsurfing veteran. Whether traveling alone or in a small group, this is an excellent chance for you to cut costs, all while making the world a smaller place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <media:content url="https://gohobo.co/assets/img/blog/tips-for-an-incredible-couchsurfing-experience/couchsurfing-girl-benjamin-combs.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpg" > </media:content>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://gohobo.co/journal/tips-for-an-incredible-couchsurfing-experience/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gohobo.co/journal/tips-for-an-incredible-couchsurfing-experience/</guid>
        
        <category>couchsurfing</category>
        
        <category>accommodation</category>
        
        
        <category>journal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Simple Tips to Make Your North Georgia Summer Vacation Even Better</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you planning to replenish your energy stores after restless working for the whole year? Summer vacations are just around the corner, and nothing but North Georgia can do wonders for you, I reckon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openstreetmap.org/search?query=North%20Georgia%2C%20USA#map=9/34.2266/-84.1580&amp;amp;layers=C&quot; title=&quot;North Georgia - OpenStreetMap&quot;&gt;North Georgia&lt;/a&gt;, a hilly area in the northern region of the US state of Georgia, is a venturesome vacation spot. The region has a great deal to offer to the tourists. The region is crammed with the natural beauty of mountains, waterfalls and rivers all around. So if you are all set to kick off your journey, some simple tips can be handy to make your trip to North Georgia a memory to cherish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-try-out-a-vacation-rental-instead-of-a-hotel&quot;&gt;1. Try out a Vacation Rental instead of a Hotel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since family fun and comfort is at the heart of any vacation trip, never compromise on it. A vacation rental can enhance the fun if your family is having more private space for themselves. Unlike a hotel, they can freely move around and enjoy the scenic beauty of North Georgia in these cabins. These rentals are available in different sizes ranging from a simple 1 room to a luxurious 5 rooms cabin. It’s advisable to book one as per your budget and family size in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you and your family are fond of adventures, a vacation rental around the hilly area is just like a cherry on cake. The mountainous beauty will give you the charismatic serenity along with a chance of multiple outdoor fun activities like hiking, camping and what not. The mountain lakes around Helen give you the opportunity to witness breathtaking fireworks and fishing as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How could one miss the chance to water tube in the world famous Chattahoochee River? A vacation rental nearby such happening place like Helen or Blue Ridge is a perfect option if your family can’t miss out this fun. Some &lt;a href=&quot;http://slidingrockcabins.com/georgia-cabins/&quot; title=&quot;Sliding Rock Cabins&quot;&gt;vacation rentals in North Georgia&lt;/a&gt; even start their hiking trails right from the cabin’s doorstep. You just can’t resist this experience with such an amazing cabin rental. You can also enjoy the calmness of the beautiful environment from the balcony of your cabin too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For kids, these vacation rentals have several indoor activities. If you want to go outside with kids, the waterparks in Blue Ridge are not far from your reach. There are plenty of vacation rentals available to make your access easy to all such water parks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-dont-miss-out-the-summer-festivals&quot;&gt;2. Don’t miss out the Summer Festivals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;North Georgia is such a happening place that keeps you rolling all the time. Though summers are scorching here, the interesting festivals can turn dog days into a never-ending fun. The “Hot Air Balloon race” in Helen is the most exciting and a must watch event. Georgia Mountain fair is another of its kind with music, arts and craft, rides, walks and what else. You’ll regret missing this event in Hiwassee. The 4th of July Celebrations in Dahlonega will leave you stunned with the most amazing fireworks. If you are a “foodie”, head on to Ellijay for the most famous food festival in May. Music Festivals also take place in summers to double the pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-shopping---a-must-in-north-georgia&quot;&gt;3. Shopping - A must in North Georgia&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t forget to shop around North Georgia. Besides enjoying the fun moments, the local souvenirs and articles remain a part of sweet memories. The local shopping stores have much to attract the visitors. The jewelry, clothes, accessories, Himalayan salt crystals, pottery and antique stuff can make shopaholics go crazy over here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-enjoy-the-food&quot;&gt;4. Enjoy the Food&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;North Georgia can satisfy your taste buds with its scrumptious food. You can enjoy variety of food in the exotic environment. The restaurants are in abundance to serve the visitors with mouthwatering dishes. As discussed earlier, food festivals are also organized in summers to suit your taste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-plan-a-bike-trail&quot;&gt;5. Plan a bike trail&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never miss out the opportunity to bike trail around &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blue_Ridge_Mountains&quot; title=&quot;Blue Ridge Mountains - Wikipedia.org&quot;&gt;Blue Ridge&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Appalachian_Trail&quot; title=&quot;Appalachian Trail - Wikipedia.org&quot;&gt;Appalachian mountains&lt;/a&gt;. Just step out of your cabin and stroll down the streets, you can start the biking trail. The trails into the woods of Chattahoochee, Dahlonega and Blue Ridge can be a life-changing experience. Not just the most challenging trails, North Georgia has beginner to intermediate trails to cater all sort of adventurers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot more to do in North Georgia. All it requires is your passion to make the most of every moment spent in the magical surrounding. The never-ending fun opportunities can make your vacations the most exciting and memorable one. Just give it a try and you’ll be recommending a trip to North Georgia to your friends next year!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <media:content url="https://gohobo.co/assets/img/blog/5-simple-tips-to-make-your-north-georgia-summer-vacation-better/north-georgia-ferris-wheel.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpg" > </media:content>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://gohobo.co/journal/5-simple-tips-to-make-your-north-georgia-summer-vacation-better/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gohobo.co/journal/5-simple-tips-to-make-your-north-georgia-summer-vacation-better/</guid>
        
        <category>vacation</category>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        
        <category>journal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>RV Camping for First Time? Avoid These Common Mistakes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;RV campers need to know a few things before they start off on their first trip. This could save them from a lot of embarrassment. It is good to learn all you can about your vehicle so you can avoid the big mistakes. Here are some common mistakes that RV newbies often make!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;being-unprepared-for-the-trip&quot;&gt;Being unprepared for the trip&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good planning makes any trip more enjoyable. When one goes out on a road trip, the purpose is relaxation and getting out of the monotony of city life. If you plan to camp out in a natural setting you need to have everything you need for all the days that you will be there. Make a budget for the trip after making all calculations. To keep on the safe side add another 20% to the budget. Next, you’ll need to choose a route. Save money on a shorter route but it also has to be safer. Make sure the route has broad enough roads with no sharp turns and low bridges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;not-learning-how-to-use-the-rv&quot;&gt;Not learning how to use the RV&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you buy a new RV you also have to learn how to operate it. Imagine leaving the campgrounds and not knowing how to dump at the dumping station. So it is good to read the manual and make sure you know how to hook up to utilities, how to disconnect and how to dump. There are many controls on the RV and you need to learn about all the power switches. Take the RV salesperson to a dump station and have him walk you through the process. Put the process on video so in case you forget you can always replay the video. Learn about the slide outs and levelling. Get all the clarifications you need. 
When you depart from the campsite, do turn the breaker off and then unplug the power. Roll up and put away the cord. If you have an RV generator turn it on when you leave. The inverter generators are ideal for RVs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;driving-off-without-disconnecting&quot;&gt;Driving off without disconnecting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most terrible mistakes that one can make is to drive off when you are still hooked up to water, sewer, and power. This can cause a considerable amount of financial damage. If you have chocked the wheels to prevent accidental movement, remove the chock, besides taking down the TV antenna.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;not-learning-how-to-park&quot;&gt;Not learning how to park&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RVs are much bigger vehicles than cars and one need to practice parking and cornering as these are tough for the rookies. This will make the trip easy on the party traveling with you. It is good to use a spotter when you park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;forgetting-to-make-reservations&quot;&gt;Forgetting to make reservations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are planning an RV trip you also need to make reservations. Many new RV users do not know the terms and condition of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bethycreek.com/&quot;&gt;RV campgrounds&lt;/a&gt;, simply because they have never used an RV park before. So check online for nearby parking camps and then make your reservations. You can find a lot of useful information at the website of the campgrounds and this will help you come to an informed decision.  Most campgrounds have strict cancellation policies, so book for only a day and then extend the stay while you are there. If you book for three days and want to leave the first day you may lose your money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;not-checking-the-coolant-in-the-fridge&quot;&gt;Not checking the coolant in the fridge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fridge keeps the food and beverages chilled and if it fails it can ruin your trip. So it is good to check the coolant level and ass some more so all can have a relaxing holiday. In some cases, the fridge can also catch fire and this can be easily avoided. Do clean the refrigerator out after you get home from every trip and keep the door open to avoid mould and mildew build up. It is good to travel with ample food so you have to worry about nothing on your trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;forgetting-necessities&quot;&gt;Forgetting necessities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most campgrounds have shops where you can buy the basic essentials. As a good trip planner, you need to pack all that you will need on your trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;not-making-a-checklist&quot;&gt;Not making a checklist!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t make a checklist for your trip, there are things you may forget to bring. Some of my recommended checklists:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Inventory&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Common RV essentials&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RV supplies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Onboard supplies
It is always good to have a checklist for both arrivals and departures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ronald Smith has spent many years travelling around different countries and also has a great passion for almost everything related to RVing, He is currently associated with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bethycreek.com/&quot; title=&quot;BethyCreek.com&quot;&gt;Bethy Creek&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <media:content url="https://gohobo.co/assets/img/blog/rv-camping-common-mistakes/rv-camping-common-mistakes.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpg" > </media:content>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://gohobo.co/journal/rv-camping-common-mistakes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gohobo.co/journal/rv-camping-common-mistakes/</guid>
        
        <category>vanlife</category>
        
        <category>camping</category>
        
        
        <category>journal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Experiences You Didn't Know Australia Could Offer You</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have ever thought about taking a trip down under, you have probably considered the roaming beaches, Sydney Opera House, barbeques and the coral reef. Australia offers many fantastic sights, experiences and opportunities for wonder, and it’s not too surprising why many people choose to travel its glorious realms every year. But it’s possible that there are plenty of attractions which you haven’t even considered, and some of them might even attract you more than the regularly billed options above. Let’s take a look at a few of the surprising things that Australia can offer you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/experience-australia/map-of-australia.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Map of Australia&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joanofjulyphotography.com/&quot;&gt;Image credit: Catarina Sousa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;skiing&quot;&gt;Skiing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you think of Australia, you normally think of sun and sea - not snow. But as it turns out, the country is actually home to one of the most popular and far-reaching skiing spots in the world. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/minube/18-reasons-why-australia_b_5396680.html&quot; title=&quot;Huffington Post - 18 Reasons Why Australia Is Travel Heaven&quot;&gt;Located in Mt. Buller&lt;/a&gt; - about a three hour drive North from Melbourne - this is a beautiful snowscape scenery which is home to a number of professional ski lodges. While you are likely to find bigger slopes in many parts of Europe, the sheer beauty of Mt. Buller’s should be enough to entice you. And if that’s not enough, don’t forget that you will have the opportunity to say something not many people can say: that you went skiing in one of the hottest countries on Earth!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;exotic-foods&quot;&gt;Exotic Foods&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might not think of Australia for its food - except perhaps the occasional barbie - but as it happens it is one of the best locations anywhere in the world for sheer variety of exotic foods. If the food is one of the major things that you always look out for while travelling, then you won’t be disappointed here, no matter where in Australia you might end up. If Asian is your thing, then you are in luck - all of the major cities, and many other areas besides, offer a huge range of Asian food, from &lt;a href=&quot;http://wokoninn.com.au/location/rouse-hill/&quot; title=&quot;Wok on Inn Restaurant Australia in Rouse Hill NSW&quot;&gt;Thai food&lt;/a&gt; to Chinese and even Japanese. You will also find some worldwide favorites, such as the classic fish and chips - and that’s not to mention the deliciously fresh seafood, something which Australians are particularly proud of. Whatever you want to eat, they’ve got it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/experience-australia/food-thai-spicy-asian.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Thai food in Australia&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pexels.com/photo/white-noodles-on-white-ceramic-plate-162993/&quot;&gt;Image credit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;festivals&quot;&gt;Festivals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best ways to spend your time while abroad is to go to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://bootsnall.com/articles/10-05/10-reasons-to-travel-to-australia-now.html&quot; title=&quot;Bootsnall.com - 10 Reasons to Go to Australia Now&quot;&gt;festival&lt;/a&gt; or two. The good news here is that Australia offers just as many as any other country on the planet, despite what you might have assumed. If you decide to travel to any of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gohobo.co/journal/awesome-australia-6-best-cities/&quot; title=&quot;GoHobo.co - 6 Best Cities in Australia&quot;&gt;major cities&lt;/a&gt; at pretty much any time of year, you are bound to discover a huge varying range of festivals, from music and food events to film or even foodie festies. Whether you are looking for a chilled event or more of a party vibe, you can be sure that Australia will have it all for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are thinking of travelling to Australia, consider giving these three experiences a shot. You might be surprised at how fully they round off your trip abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <media:content url="https://gohobo.co/assets/img/blog/experience-australia/festival-in-australia.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpg" > </media:content>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://gohobo.co/journal/3-experiences-you-didnt-know-australia-could-offer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gohobo.co/journal/3-experiences-you-didnt-know-australia-could-offer/</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>contributed</category>
        
        <category>australia</category>
        
        
        <category>journal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Xi'an: A Culture Vulture's Paradise</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When you think of China, images of emperors, ancient dynasties, and historic trade routes come to mind. If you love venturing deep into a country’s history, then the Chinese city of Xi’an could be just what you are looking for. Xi’an was the capital of many Chinese dynasties and formed an integral part of the Silk Road. Its roots are firmly in the past yet also shows off China’s optimistic and promising future. The province of Shaanxi is the second most visited in China because of its rich culture, the famous Terracotta Warriors and magnificent museums. If you’re tempted by a jaunt to China, take a look at why Xi’an should be high up on your list of destinations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-food&quot;&gt;The Food&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Shaanxi province of which Xi’an is the capital is more culinary diverse than most, partly due to its Muslim population. This influence on the Chinese cuisine has made for a unique eating experience for tourists. Mutton and pork dumplings will be served from one street vendor while next to him a master of the wok will be stir frying lamb with spices and nuts. With a specific &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.travelchinaguide.com/attraction/shaanxi/xian/moslem-street.htm&quot; title=&quot;Travel China guide - Muslim Quarter&quot;&gt;Muslim Quarter&lt;/a&gt;, the city celebrates its special culinary influences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/xian-culture-vulture-paradise/chinese-cuisine-dimsum.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Chinese Cuisine - Dimsum&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/asian-food-dimsum-cuisine-soy-2090944/&quot;&gt;Image credit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep an eye on where the locals go and follow. Some the least salubrious eateries that forego the glitz of a shiny sign can end up serving the most delicious morsels. The flat handmade noodles and the quail egg kebabs with a spicy Sichuan sauce are a must.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;travel-by-bicycle&quot;&gt;Travel by Bicycle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no better way to tour any city than by bike. Being a walled city, Xi’an allows you to cycle the entire perimeter of the city stopping off to marvel at the views and purchase tiny Terracotta Warrior souvenir figurines along the way. The walls were built by the Emperors of the ancient Ming dynasty, and with exceptional renovations over the years, they are still in remarkably good shape. If cycling sounds a little daunting, the walls are relatively flat, and there is always the option of &lt;a href=&quot;https://momentummag.com/why-you-should-explore-cities-by-bike/&quot; title=&quot;MomentumMag - Why You Should Explore Cities by Bike&quot;&gt;hiring an electric bike&lt;/a&gt; to make the journey a little less taxing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/xian-culture-vulture-paradise/china-terracotta-warriors.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Terracotta Warriors&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/terracotta-warriors-xi-an-china-2542028/&quot;&gt;Image credit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;where-to-rest-your-head&quot;&gt;Where To Rest Your Head&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are over 2,600 hotels in Xi’an, and these are only the ones listed on Tripadvisor. It can be quite daunting deciding where you should stay. To assess &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.regalhotel.com/regal-airport-hotel-xian-hotel/en/home/home.html&quot; title=&quot;Regal Hotel - China&quot;&gt;which Xi’an hotel can fulfill your needs&lt;/a&gt; you need to think about whether you want to stay out of town, right in the center of things or closer to the airport. The key is to make sure you are based near a transport hub so that you can reach any cultural spot with ease. You may want to visit Huaqing Palace, the TangBo Art Museum or head out of the city to enjoy &lt;a href=&quot;https://gohobo.co/journal/what-nature-is-to-me/&quot; title=&quot;GoHobo - What Nature is to Me&quot;&gt;a spot of nature&lt;/a&gt; at Cuihua Mountain. Make sure you are within five minutes walk of a metro, and your traveling will be a whole lot easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/xian-culture-vulture-paradise/china-architecture-at-night.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Chinese architecture at night&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/china-the-scenery-xi-an-history-1247764/&quot;&gt;Image credit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When making plans to visit the wonderful country of China, ensure that you don’t miss out the city of Xi’an. The food, nature, people and culture make for one of the most rewarding traveling experiences you will ever embark on in your life.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <media:content url="https://gohobo.co/assets/img/blog/xian-culture-vulture-paradise/chinese-cuisine-dimsum.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpg" > </media:content>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://gohobo.co/journal/xian-a-culture-vulture-paradise/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gohobo.co/journal/xian-a-culture-vulture-paradise/</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>contributed</category>
        
        
        <category>journal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Awesome Australia: The 6 Best Cities Down Under</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For people all over the world, Australia is a dream destination. The laid-back lifestyle, incredible weather and stunning natural scenery are just three factors that draw people to this great land. But beyond this, the cities ‘Down Under’ are simply out of this world! Job opportunities, education, art, culture and entertainment are all here in abundance, so if you are considering coming to any of them to work or live, there is no doubt that you are making a fine decision. In this post, we will look a little closer at Australia’s six most celebrated cities and what it is that makes them so great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/awesome-australia-6-best-cities/sydney-at-night.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sydney Australia at night from the harbour&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pexels.com/photo/dawn-australia-sydney-reflection-57389/&quot;&gt;Image credit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;melbourne&quot;&gt;Melbourne&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have ever been backpacking around Europe, you will already be well-aware that every other person that you meet seems to be from &lt;a href=&quot;https://theworldlovesmelbourne.com/lifestyle/arts-culture/133-top-10-reasons-to-visit-melbourne.html&quot; title=&quot;The World Loves Melbourne - 10 reasons to visit&quot;&gt;Melbourne&lt;/a&gt;! But that doesn’t mean that the population is shrinking. In fact, over 4.5 million people call this city home, and it is quickly catching up with the biggest Australian city of Sydney. Melbourne is quite diverse in its climate - coastal conditions are cool as breezy, while the inland is hot and dry. One of the main things that the city known for is its culture. All kinds of festivals and events take place here every year, and it is also packed with galleries and theatres. If you have a hipster bone in your body, you will also be delighted by the number of artisan coffee shops that are around!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sydney&quot;&gt;Sydney&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The city that many people mistake as being the capital of Australia, Sydney is perhaps best-known for the architecturally unique Opera House. Some of the other popular cultural attractions include the Queen Victoria Building, the Museum of Contemporary Art, and the Australian Museum. Over five million people live in Sydney, and it is also renowned for its merging of cultures from all over the world. Inside the main city centre itself, it is both bustling and visually attractive. Move a little towards the suburbs and you will find that there are all kinds of unique and appealing neighbourhoods to explore. And there is no doubt that &lt;a href=&quot;https://gohobo.co/journal/best-rural-destinations-in-rural-new-south-wales/&quot; title=&quot;GoHobo - Best Rural destinations in New South Wales&quot;&gt;New South Wales&lt;/a&gt; is one of the most beautiful states to visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/awesome-australia-6-best-cities/sydney-opera-house-at-night.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pexels.com/photo/australia-house-sydney-vivid-54610/&quot;&gt;Image credit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;perth&quot;&gt;Perth&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standing in the centre of Perth, you would hardly be able to tell what a geographically remote part of the country you are in - its nearest neighbour city is located over 1,300 miles away! Some of the country’s most stunning natural wonders are located on this side of the country, and you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.burswoodcarrentals.com.au/&quot; title=&quot;Burswood Car Rentals&quot;&gt;hire cars at Burswood Car Rentals&lt;/a&gt; to reach them. But even within the city boundary itself, there are plenty of beautiful local beaches and cultural attractions to enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;brisbane&quot;&gt;Brisbane&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third largest city in Australia is Brisbane, the capital of Queensland. Art and technology are the twin enterprises that drive this city forward, and this has also helped to boost tourism in the area. A total of nine universities also ensure that the student population is big and thriving. There are also a host of nature-inspired activities to take in including the Lone Pine Koala Sanctuary and Brisbane Forest Park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/awesome-australia-6-best-cities/brisbane-koala.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pexels.com/photo/adorable-animal-cute-fun-532543/&quot;&gt;Image credit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;adelaide&quot;&gt;Adelaide&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tucked away between the hills and the oceans, Adelaide is renowned for its wine and food culture. There is nowhere better to enjoy this than visiting the &lt;a href=&quot;http://southaustralia.traveller.com.au/article/east-vs-west-your-guide-to-adelaides-laneway-bars/&quot; title=&quot;South Australia Traveller - Adelaide's Laneway Bars&quot;&gt;Laneway Bars&lt;/a&gt; where you can find cuisine from all over the world. If you are looking for fresh produce, there is nowhere better to visit than the Central Market. For history buffs, a visit to the historic port area is certainly in order, and you can even kayak along the Port River to get a totally different impression of the city. And the local zoo is one of the best in the country with more than 1,800 different animals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;canberra&quot;&gt;Canberra&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The actual capital of Australia often gets a bad rep, but this sprawling urban centre actually has a great variety of museums and landmarks, as well as a buzzing nightlife. The economic wealth of the city means that job opportunities are rife, and it is also the centre of Australian politics. The ten-day Canberra Festival draws in people from all over the country to celebrate the best of music in a wide range of different genres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, hopefully you have a better idea about six of Australia’s finest cities. Each one of them has plenty of unique opportunities and attractions to visit. If you are planning a move out here, it is highly likely that you will call one of these places home, and even if you are just planning a visit, they are great bases from which to explore the rest of the country.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <media:content url="https://gohobo.co/assets/img/blog/awesome-australia-6-best-cities/sydney-opera-house-at-night.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpg" > </media:content>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://gohobo.co/journal/awesome-australia-6-best-cities/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gohobo.co/journal/awesome-australia-6-best-cities/</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>contributed</category>
        
        
        <category>journal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stay Out Of Trouble On Your Travels</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are lots of people who want to travel and see the world. Perhaps you can, but it is important to realize that traveling can be quite dangerous. Particularly, if you don’t think about where you’re going, what you’re going to do when you get there and how you’re going to afford it. You need to make sure you protect yourself and avoid the danger that comes with travel adventures. Here are some great little tidbits for making sure that your travel dream doesn’t become a terrible nightmare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;have-backups&quot;&gt;Have Backups&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are probably &lt;a href=&quot;https://gohobo.co/journal/travel-smarter-sharing-economy/&quot;&gt;taking money with you&lt;/a&gt; on your travels. It’s best to have a few different sources of money in case you lose one of them or they are stolen. So, you might have a travel currency card with the main portion of your money. But you also want some cash in your pocket which can be useful for tips and other payments related to social etiquette. Finally, you should take a credit card with you. This will provide you with an extra level of security because you will always have enough money to get out of a scrape. It’s worth noting that these financial sources should not be kept in the same place. If you are staying in a hotel with a safe make sure you have some money tucked away for emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/stay-out-of-trouble/backup-travel-money.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Always carry backup funds when travelling&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;take-government-advice&quot;&gt;Take Government Advice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your government regularly updates the areas of the world that are not safe to travel. There are lots of reasons why an area might be unsafe. It could be in the midst of political upheaval such as Egypt or be a location linked to terrorist activity. Again, Egypt currently fits the bill here and many governments are advising that their citizens don’t travel there at all. You can learn more about parts of Egypt that are not currently safe on &lt;a href=&quot;http://home.bt.com/lifestyle/travel/&quot;&gt;BT Travel&lt;/a&gt;. If you are going to a part of the world that could be considered dangerous, make sure you hire a guide. They will be able to keep you as safe as possible during your trip and make sure you steer clear of dangerous areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/stay-out-of-trouble/travel-advisories.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Consider government advice on travel advisories&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Image credit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pexels.com/u/davidmceachan/&quot;&gt;David McEachan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-full-insurance&quot;&gt;Get Full Insurance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should make sure that you have full travel insurance when you set off on an adventure. It is vital that you are protected for any financial losses and in medical emergencies. At the very least, you should have the medical travel insurance to ensure that you can be treated for any injury or illness that you could experience on vacation. Some people do avoid getting the right travel coverage to cut costs. However, if you explore a site such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gobear.com/ph/travel-insurance&quot;&gt;GoBear.com&lt;/a&gt;, you will see that it is possible to get full coverage without paying a fortune. In fact, you can protect yourself for a fraction of the cost of the holiday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/stay-out-of-trouble/travel-insurance.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Travel insurance is a good idea&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;be-honest&quot;&gt;Be Honest&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you enter a country, customs and immigration will always ask you about the purpose you have in the country and the activities that you may participate in. If you are as honest as possible, this is the best way to ensure that you do get help from the authorities if things do go wrong. You might also wish to inquire about the rules and laws of the country, armed with the knowledge that they are likely not the same as those of your home nation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/stay-out-of-trouble/airport-traveling.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Be honest with customs officers and airport security&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you take this advice, you can make sure you are safe no matter where you are traveling to in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <media:content url="https://gohobo.co/assets/img/blog/stay-out-of-trouble/travel-advisories.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpg" > </media:content>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://gohobo.co/journal/stay-out-of-trouble-on-your-travels/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gohobo.co/journal/stay-out-of-trouble-on-your-travels/</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>contributed</category>
        
        
        <category>journal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Barcelona's Best Buildings</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Those with a lust for travel will no doubt have the city of Barcelona somewhere on their ‘to-do’ list. Spain’s second city (and the capital of Catalonia), plays host to some of the most spectacular icons of European architecture with a diverse landscape bustling with gothic mansions and ‘&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.barcelona-life.com/barcelona/modernisme&quot;&gt;modernista&lt;/a&gt;’ masterpieces. Barcelona enjoyed a relative anonymity as seaside tourism took off in the 1960s while holiday makers from the UK and the rest of Europe flocked to the sandy beaches of Ibiza and Marbella for sun, sea and sangria. But ever since the city hosted the 1992 olympics it’s been awash with the clicking shutters of thousands of tourists’ cameras.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The spectacular Catedral (La Seu) is one of the most beautiful and jaw dropping masterpieces of gothic architecture in the world, but there’s a whole lot more to the city than this beloved icon. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecrazytourist.com/15-best-things-barcelona-spain/&quot;&gt;Barcelona, Spain&lt;/a&gt;’s rich history and culture has seen a range of cultural influences in its architecture resulting in one of Europe’s most beautiful and fascinating skylines. Let’s take a tour through some of these brilliant buildings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;la-sagrada-familia&quot;&gt;La Sagrada Familia&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you only see one building in Barcelona it should be this astonishing, unfinished masterpiece. Every square foot of wall space in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sagradafamilia.org/en/&quot;&gt;La Sagrada Familia&lt;/a&gt; is a masterfully crafted work of art. Attracting 2.8 million visitors a year it is by far the most visited monument in Spain, with its recent consecration by the Pope in 2010 causing an even greater boom in visiting tourists from all faiths. The temple’s architect Antoni Gaudi saw its completion as more than his life’s work, it was his all-consuming obsession and he regarded it as his Holy mission to see its completion. While work may continue well into the 2040s, there’s still plenty of stone sculpted wonderment to be found here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;la-pedrere&quot;&gt;La Pedrere&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another of Antoni Gaudi ingenious works, this undulating oddity looks almost like a Salvador Dali painting brought to life. Completed in 1910 it was originally intended to function as an apartment building and office block, commissioned by Pere Mila. Mila has just married the wealthy widow Roser Guardiola and he knew how to spend her money in style. ‘Casa Mila’ as it was originally known is one of the first buildings in the world to have its own in-built parking space. The building now hosts visitors drawn to the eccentricity of Gaudi’s work and while the best viewing is in the spectacular roof with it’s chess piece like chimneys, the apartment itself is still a shrine to 20th century wealth and excess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;torre-agbar&quot;&gt;Torre Agbar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This ultra modern cucumber shaped building is a hot blooded Latin cousin of London’s famous ‘&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.visitlondon.com/things-to-do/sightseeing/london-attraction/the-gherkin#HYpS0s8bkKqbLuPy.97&quot;&gt;Gherkin&lt;/a&gt;’.  While the English monument is a primly restrained tower of glass and steel, Torre Agbar (completed in 2005) is more like a crystal finger pointing at the sky, shimmering in vivid shades of blue and red at night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;palau-de-la-música-catalana&quot;&gt;Palau de la Música Catalana&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This shrine to Catalanian music is not only Barcelona’s premier concert hall but a masterpiece of Modernista architecture. The central glass and metal structure paints the beautiful interior with light while the ornate exterior lures in thousands of tourists from around the world every year. The building is the only concert hall in this style to be listed as a UNESCO heritage site.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <media:content url="https://gohobo.co/assets/img/blog/barcelonas-best-buildings.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpg" > </media:content>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://gohobo.co/journal/barcelonas-best-buildings/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gohobo.co/journal/barcelonas-best-buildings/</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>contributed</category>
        
        <category>Spain</category>
        
        
        <category>journal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why You Should Live and Travel in a Van Pt. 1</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;vandwelling-puts-things-into-perspective&quot;&gt;Vandwelling puts things into perspective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the years, I accumulated so much crap. I felt certain things held a
sentimental value and so I held onto them. This was by far one of the
largest hurdles (at least for myself) when moving into the van.
Some of my stuff was really hard to let go of - at first. After dropping
some of my more sentimental items, I realized I wouldn’t really miss
them, nor have a need for them. This is going to sound super-cheese,
but everything important to me was either in my head, or could fit into
a backpack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sell-your-stuff-to-fund-your-adventures-or-give-it-away-and-feel-good&quot;&gt;Sell your stuff to fund your adventures, or give it away and feel good&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the weeks before moving into our van Zeus, I let go of things I’d been hanging on to for years and even decades. It felt great. We managed to make a pretty sweet pile of cash and made some people happy by handing out the remnants of our frivolous material stash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Part of the charm of living in a van is the freedom to hit the road whenever you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first couple weeks in the van were anxiety-ridden and stressful. It’s a huge move, mentally and physically, to give up your own room or a large shared living quarters for 236 cubic feet of inefficient 70’s camper-van living. In the first weeks, we learned the true value of space. We ended up dropping even more of our stuff, realizing we were still hanging on to things we had no use for. We simplified and minimized everything we could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were so into minimalism, that we started upgrading the things we did have to keep. Smaller, lighter, more efficient kitchen utensils, plates, bedding, towels, shoes, and clothing; a single jacket to rule them all, a high quality breathable sweater, several pairs of high-quality light hiking socks, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;down-with-consumerism&quot;&gt;Down with consumerism!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a precursor to moving out of our static residence, we gathered all of our bills and monthly commitments, sorting through and tying up any and all loose ends. In doing so, we quickly realized how much money we would be saving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Van life does have it’s monthly payment responsibilities, like a gym pass, maintenance fund, cell phone, credit card, etcetera, but we were able to drop hydro bills and rent, which felt like a huge step in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The things you own, end up owning you”. - Chuck Palahniuk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s truly amazing how much invisible stuff (also known as debt) we needlessly accumulate. Unsurprisingly, months into living the van life, we were realizing we really didn’t miss much of the old life. I mean, the sheer weight of rent and hydro being lifted was exciting enough, but there are so many more politics involved with renting an apartment, damage deposits and roommates that I will never again miss*.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;travelling-in-a-van-is-fun&quot;&gt;Travelling in a van is fun&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the charm of living in a van is the freedom to hit the road whenever you want. Even for vandwellers living in a city, getting out is just that much easier. It just becomes a way of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-roadtrip-with-all-the-comforts-of-home&quot;&gt;A roadtrip with all the comforts of home&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roadtripping in your home-on-wheels provides an incredible stepping stone to adventure. Save on accommodation or go camping whenever and wherever you want; city, forest, suburbs or beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At any point in your trip, you could stop and camp at that hidden gem of a lake you spotted from the highway, skip over the prairies in one shot, pull over for a comfortable nap in your own bed, barbecue, latté, cocktail, a bowl of cereal, whatever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;make-your-own-damn-schedule&quot;&gt;Make your own damn schedule&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This freedom is unmatched. If you’ve got your food and gas sorted, you now have the freedom to make your own schedule (assuming you are no longer on somebody else’s) with all of your bases covered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having this flexibility is sure to keep your stress levels at bay. Nothing dampens the mood like a tight schedule or unruly itinerary while travelling. Sometimes, you just want to lay in your hammock, or listen to your favourite radio program, or just enjoy the silence, far from humanity, instead of meeting the rest of the tour group for salsa lessons around the pool. No hotel reservations, no rental car return times… if that’s your thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;your-windows-frame-the-landscape&quot;&gt;Your windows frame the landscape&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any interest at all in nature, architecture, urban planning, design, engineering, history, geology or the world around you, you’ll truly enjoy the view. The view is ever-changing, yet transforms whenever you want it to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone who’s had the opportunity to find themselves far from light pollution can speak to one of the most amazingly mind-blowing views ever. The unpolluted night sky. I won’t get too poetic about this subject, but dang! This is something we don’t get in the city. In fact, I’m sure there are many people who’ve never seen a true night sky in all their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Travelling by van is the only way to get a feel for the entire landscape. Every hill provides a new perspective, every valley - a new horizon. Driving away from the sunrise is a fantastic experience and one that will always remain with me. There’s something about hitting the road early, ready to see new things, feel new feels, and write new words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, my daydreaming above only covers a fraction of vanlife. Most often, we’ll be driving through cities or between towns. This also provides an incredible view into the lives of locals, of history and of culture. It’s the perfect way to get acquainted with a new city of residence, get your bearings, and mentally map your next itinerary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;to-be-continued&quot;&gt;To Be Continued…&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <media:content url="https://gohobo.co/assets/img/blog/why-you-should-live-travel-in-a-van.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpg" > </media:content>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://gohobo.co/journal/why-you-should-live-and-travel-in-a-van-p1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gohobo.co/journal/why-you-should-live-and-travel-in-a-van-p1/</guid>
        
        <category>vanlife</category>
        
        <category>inspiration</category>
        
        
        <category>journal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Best Rural Destinations in New South Wales, Australia</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Getting out of Sydney for a long weekend and spending it in the countryside is a great way to clear your head, and get back down to earth. With plenty to do if you’re a young family, couple or a solo traveller, why not escape the concrete madness? Sip delicious vino overlooking the canola fields that roll into wheat paddocks. Cuddle up in front of a fire and gorge on fresh pizza and belly warming cocktails. Hike to the top of Australia’s largest mountain, and maybe even see snow. Or just relax in the valley and watch the native wildlife in abundance. Rural New South Wales literally has something for everyone&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/best-rural-destinations-nsw/best-rural-destinations-new-south-wales.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A field of grain in NSW, Australia - by Giles Alexander&quot; title=&quot;A field of grains under a blue sky in Australia.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Image credit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/overwatering/4287937488/&quot; title=&quot;Flickr.com&quot;&gt;Giles Alexander&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;young&quot;&gt;Young&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With so many surrounding towns, and farm life, Young is a wonderful place to come back down to earth. Spend the day sipping on locally grown grapes at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.visithilltopsregion.com.au/Business-Directory/grove-estate-winery&quot; title=&quot;Grove Estate Winery, New South Wales, Australia&quot;&gt;Grove Estate&lt;/a&gt;, venture to some of the weekend markets selling fresh produce, honey, and souvenirs. If you happen to visiting during fruit picking, partake in the crazy festivities of Cherry season. Young is also known as the Cherry capital of Australia, and you will soon see why. Drop into some of the local towns nearby with the iconic Wombat a short distance away, or Jugiong 30 minutes drive along the Murrumbidgee River. On your way back to Sydney drop into either Long track Pantry, or Barnestore Emporium for a spot of morning tea before getting on the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/best-rural-destinations-nsw/best-rural-destinations-new-south-wales_grove-estate.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Two massive wine barrels in a barn in NSW, by Deborah &amp;amp; Kevin&quot; title=&quot;Two massive wine barrels in a barn in NSW.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Image credit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/eatdrinkseedo/7715159016/&quot; title=&quot;Flickr.com&quot;&gt;Deborah &amp;amp; Kevin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mudgee&quot;&gt;Mudgee&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you craving a wine? How does a weekend away exploring one of the most peaceful wine regions in Australia sound? Nibble on chip and dip whilst overlooking the beautiful Mudgee area, drop into Logan winery for a drop of Chardonnay, or Skimstone for an incredible Italian Sangiovese. Want to get outside? Head to the Drip Gorge or the Gap Nature Reserve for sensational views of the area. If, after a long day of frolicking around multiple vineyards you find yourself becoming a little peckish, drop by Di’ Lusso Estate for an Italian feast for dinner. If you are looking for somewhere beautiful to stay, look into any of the local &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.visitnsw.com/destinations/country-nsw/mudgee-area/mudgee/accommodation&quot; title=&quot;Accommodation in Mudgee, New South Wales, visitnsw.com&quot;&gt;homesteads, or bed and breakfast’s&lt;/a&gt;. These cute little abodes offer a more realistic depiction of life in the country, and give you that homely feel that you want on short getaways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/best-rural-destinations-nsw/best-rural-destinations-new-south-wales_bed-and-breakfast.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Image credit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/22616984@N07/3533120236/&quot; title=&quot;Flickr.com&quot;&gt;Ian Sutton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bathurst&quot;&gt;Bathurst&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bathurst is a great place to adventure to if you want a taste of the country, but don’t want to loose on out on some city luxuries. It’s a great place for families, or young travellers, with an abundance of activities to keep everyone entertained. Take a brewery tour at Two Heads, and explore beer making, with some tasty treats at the end. Head to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.churchbar.com.au/&quot; title=&quot;Dinner in Bathurst, New South Wales, churchbar.com.au&quot;&gt;Church Bar&lt;/a&gt; for dinner, cuddle up in front of the crackling fire and munch on some delicious pizza. Drive around Mount Panorama like a real V8 driver, or visit the local ice creamery for a diner style experience. Still hungry for adventure? Head to the local caves, drink gin at Four Pillars, eat a healthy breakfast at The Hub, or take a tour of one of the historical locations within Bathurst. Visiting the former Savings Bank, Woolston or Abercrombie house is a great way to finish your time in this quaint old mining town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/best-rural-destinations-nsw/best-rural-destinations-new-south-wales_kangaroo-valley.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An old trailer deep in lush green forest in NSW, by Eddy Milfort&quot; title=&quot;An old trailer deep in lush green forest in NSW&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Image credit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/eddymilfort/14208594179/&quot; title=&quot;Flickr.com&quot;&gt;Eddy Milfort&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;kangaroo-valley&quot;&gt;Kangaroo Valley&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bushwalking heaven! This foggy valley South of Sydney is a nature-lover’s dream. With beautiful outdoor walks, kayaking on the river, and the magnificent &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.visitnsw.com/destinations/south-coast/jervis-bay-and-shoalhaven/kangaroo-valley/attractions/gerringong-falls&quot; title=&quot;Tourist attractions, visitnsw.com&quot;&gt;Gerringong falls&lt;/a&gt; you will busy for the whole weekend, without even trying. If you are still lacking your country fix, then drop into the local Pioneer Village Museum and read up on the history of Kangaroo Valley including the amazingly regal Hampden Bridge. Don’t forget to make a stop at Tallowa Dam on your way out, part of the supply scheme giving the Shoalhaven area water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; 
 &lt;br /&gt;
– 
 &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;
Olivia is a traveller, foodie and amateur photographer. Having just come back from a trip to Sri Lanka she is currently inspired and can’t stop cooking up lentil curries, and okra feasts. Olivia’s love for food has inspired her to book the next big adventure,
with a bag in tow she will jet off to South East Asia later in the year. Check out her &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/oliblost/&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://greatlost.com/&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; for more! 
&lt;/small&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <media:content url="https://gohobo.co/assets/img/blog/best-rural-destinations-nsw/best-rural-destinations_new-south-wales.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpg" > </media:content>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://gohobo.co/journal/best-rural-destinations-in-rural-new-south-wales/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gohobo.co/journal/best-rural-destinations-in-rural-new-south-wales/</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>adventure</category>
        
        
        <category>journal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What's in my Backpack: Camping Edition</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I grew up camping across Southwestern British Columbia through all four seasons. Family camping trips though the Kootenays as a child, winter camping as a Scout, and real roughing-it camping in my late teens and early twenties. These days I’m a family camper myself, sharing my love of the great outdoors with my children - as my parents did with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-camping--hiking-kit&quot;&gt;My Camping &amp;amp; Hiking Kit&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years I’ve tried, tested, and amassed a well-rounded backpack full of camping and hiking must-haves. Although none of this is top-of-the-line gear, it has served me extremely well. Everything in my current &lt;em&gt;kit&lt;/em&gt; is and has been in use on multiple trips into the wild and used on numerous occasions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-lone-pines-edible--medicinal-plants-of-the-rockies&quot;&gt;1. Lone Pine’s Edible &amp;amp; Medicinal Plants of the Rockies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is easily one of my favourite books. I’ve read it countless time, and it’s been on plenty of adventures. It’s a big book to carry in your backpack - but it’s a real gem and a constant source of knowledge. Through this book, I’ve been able to build up a working knowledge of useful plants - both delicious and unpalatable. It’s helped me create some soothing backwoods brews, some tasty smoking mixtures and some fun campfire cooking experiments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More recently I’ve picked up its companion &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2j9AYAf&quot;&gt;Edible &amp;amp; Medicinal Plants of Canada&lt;/a&gt; (to get my edibles fix for the rest of the Country), and although useful, it’s not nearly as comprehensive (&lt;em&gt;obviously&lt;/em&gt;) as it’s more specific sibling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-pin-do=&quot;embedPin&quot; data-pin-width=&quot;large&quot; data-pin-terse=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.pinterest.com/pin/93942342211086208/&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2jxlrGY&quot;&gt;
    &lt;button class=&quot;btn--cta&quot;&gt;
        Buy it now
    &lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-leatherman-fuse-multitool&quot;&gt;2. Leatherman Fuse Multitool&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best tool in my kit - hands down. This multitool has been with me for at least 12 years. It holds a unique collection of tools, it makes for a pretty handy tool to have around the house, but it really shines in the outdoors. This tool has shaved hundreds of pounds of kindling, its hooks from dozens of fish faces, pulled pots of boiling water from the fire, carved cooking sticks and spears, trimmed rope, opened hundreds of cans, and has seen four different provinces and over a decade of constant use. If it broke - I’d buy another the next day. Luckily Leatherman has a 25-year parts warranty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BDR4NHQBn3y/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A post shared by Christopher Pittam (@cjp1995)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2016-03-23T02:48:38+00:00&quot;&gt;Mar 22, 2016 at 7:48pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2j9pVXA&quot;&gt;
    &lt;button class=&quot;btn--cta&quot;&gt;
        Buy it now
    &lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-ruko-nylon-handle-survival-knife&quot;&gt;3. Ruko Nylon Handle Survival Knife&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got this piece for my 17th birthday. I’m now 30, and it’s still going strong. It’s a pretty cheap knife - at around $50 - but it’s durable and strong enough to make firewood if you don’t have a hatchet.  The handle is a touch nylon and has some nice battle scars, but the grip fits very nicely in the hand, and it’s got a strong hilt. Great for smashing open nuts or crushing leaves for your tea!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fpermalink.php%3Fstory_fbid%3D1108574522573585%26id%3D1089746237789747&amp;amp;width=auto&amp;amp;show_text=false&amp;amp;appId=474954152698654&amp;amp;height=509&quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; height=&quot;509&quot; style=&quot;border:none;overflow:hidden&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rukoproducts.com/index.php?target=products&amp;amp;mode=search&amp;amp;subcats=Y&amp;amp;type=extended&amp;amp;avail=Y&amp;amp;pshort=Y&amp;amp;pfull=Y&amp;amp;pname=Y&amp;amp;pkeywords=Y&amp;amp;cid=45&amp;amp;q=5161&amp;amp;x=0&amp;amp;y=0&quot;&gt;
    &lt;button class=&quot;btn--cta&quot;&gt;
        Buy it now
    &lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-black-diamond-headlamp&quot;&gt;4. Black Diamond Headlamp&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright, I’m starting to feel old now. This headlamp is still chugging along with 9 years of use. The batteries seem to last forever on low light - easily a couple hours nightly over a few weekend camping trips, with little or no drain with disuse. It provides a pretty powerful light, with 3 different modes; &lt;em&gt;bright&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;less-bright&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;blinking&lt;/em&gt;. It’s been dropped numerous times but it’s a true beast. It’s definitely a little large and heavy by today’s headlamp standards, but it does its job well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:33.98148148148148% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BLKnpHvgIpg/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A post shared by Black Diamond Equipment (@blackdiamond)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2016-10-05T03:20:23+00:00&quot;&gt;Oct 4, 2016 at 8:20pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2jkYYxy&quot;&gt;
    &lt;button class=&quot;btn--cta&quot;&gt;
        Buy it now
    &lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-marmot-minimalist&quot;&gt;5. Marmot Minimalist&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Living on the West Coast merits a pretty good rain shell. After a few months of research (5 years ago) and poking around for deals, I came across the Minimalist. Weighing in at less than a pound, it’s super light, Gore-Tex Paclite enforced, very comfortable, has a great range of movement, it’s got PitZips (I hike warm),  and most importantly - it’s waterproof; It got me comfortably through several West Coast winters warm and dry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about 4.5 years, the sleeve cuffs have started to come apart, and it’s waterproofing has been reduced significantly - even after a couple re-treatments. Overall I’m pretty impressed, but I’m leaning more towards a Patagonia rain shell due to their incredible warranty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-pin-do=&quot;embedPin&quot; data-pin-width=&quot;large&quot; data-pin-terse=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.pinterest.com/pin/93942342211086178/&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//assets.pinterest.com/js/pinit.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2jl7Umv&quot;&gt;
    &lt;button class=&quot;btn--cta&quot;&gt;
        Buy it now
    &lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;6-mountain-equipment-co-op-60l-backpack&quot;&gt;6. Mountain Equipment Co-op 60L Backpack&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although seemingly generic, this backpack is quite light, comfortable, and well-designed. It has some great features, including the placement of its pockets, a flexible water bottle pocket with waterline exit (for your Platypus or Camelback system), industrial zippers, adjustable packing area, compression straps, and aluminum reinforcements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This beast has been to a few different countries with me and on several hiking excursions. I would position it more geared towards outdoor backpacking than travel due to the straps and doo-dads on the exterior, but it’s also pretty well-suited as a checked bag once you cinch all the straps, and wrap it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve got to hand it to MEC for their product longevity and toughness; this thing has been tossed and squished, dropped and dragged, and it still looks new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-pin-do=&quot;embedPin&quot; data-pin-width=&quot;large&quot; data-pin-terse=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.pinterest.com/pin/93942342211086166/&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mec.ca/en/product/5039-728/Forge-65-Backpack&quot;&gt;
    &lt;button class=&quot;btn--cta&quot;&gt;
        Buy it now
    &lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;7-katadyn-hiker-pro-microfilter&quot;&gt;7. Katadyn Hiker Pro Microfilter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been carrying this with me throughout my adventures over the last 5 years. Although I’ve only used it a handful of times - it’s definitely redeemed some potentially dead-end camping excursions. I’ve tested it in some pretty dire circumstances, including extracting water from swampy stagnant mud puddles, with great results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notably, it takes a while to actual pump/filter enough water to gather enough to quench your thirst, but there are some tricks I’ve learned to smooth out the sometimes tedious process of extracting drinkable water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I always keep a kerchief as part of my kit, which I use as a preliminary filter to at least clear the substrate (you know, the floaties and dirt).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, once you’ve pumped and filtered enough water, be sure to let it sit for about 5 minutes to let any gasses dissipate. This will remove a lot of the unpleasant smells and results in a better-tasting refreshment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, this is a great piece which I always carry with me. I never know when I’m going to need it, but when I do it can be a lifesaver!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:58.93518518518519% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BTvw-7eA17v/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A post shared by Katadyn_Group (@katadyn_group)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2017-05-06T09:45:04+00:00&quot;&gt;May 6, 2017 at 2:45am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2jxghL2&quot;&gt;
    &lt;button class=&quot;btn--cta&quot;&gt;
        Buy it now
    &lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;8-hotcore-odyssey-sleeping-bag&quot;&gt;8. Hotcore Odyssey Sleeping Bag&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, this purchase was a compulsive one, as I was planning a backpacking trip and running low on time, so without much research, this sleeping bag was purchased. 13 years, 3 continents, and 6 countries later, this bag is still kicking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve used this sleeping bag in a number of climates from tropical to sub-zero and it’s done it’s job well. On the plus side, it’s super light, very durable, and packs quite small, but although it’s rated to -10°C, it’s only suitable down to about 2 or 3°C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just over the last couple weeks, I pulled the zipper too hard and warped some of the [plastic] teeth. This happened on the bottom side, so I can no longer zip it up. For now, it will make a fine quilt, but I think for the small price of $80 CAD this bag was easily worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-pin-do=&quot;embedPin&quot; data-pin-width=&quot;large&quot; data-pin-terse=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.pinterest.com/pin/93942342211086134/&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.greatadventure.ca/00cart/candypress/scripts/prodView.asp?idproduct=2406&quot;&gt;
    &lt;button class=&quot;btn--cta&quot;&gt;
        Buy it now
    &lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;9-therm-a-rest-z-lite-sleeping-sol-mattress&quot;&gt;9. Therm-a-rest Z Lite Sleeping Sol Mattress&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another compulsive purchase which most definitely ended up worth every penny of the $45 CAD I paid for it. Since there are few downsides to this piece of kit, I’ll start with the negative; It’s a little bulky but can be easily folded and strapped to the outside of your pack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extremely comfortable, very light, and quite insulating, this mattress did the trick. I opted for the 3/4 version, as it was a little smaller, and I sleep on my side, so my hips need the padding. The pad is thick enough to get away with sleeping on some pretty rough terrain, and with a groundsheet, or in a tent it fared just fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:41.342592592592595% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BTz1UnTjVRr/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A post shared by Fin &amp;amp; Feather (@finfeather)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2017-05-07T23:39:56+00:00&quot;&gt;May 7, 2017 at 4:39pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2jx6cO2&quot;&gt;
    &lt;button class=&quot;btn--cta&quot;&gt;
        Buy it now
    &lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;10-fiskars-chopping-axe&quot;&gt;10. Fiskars Chopping Axe&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For years, I carried a Fiskars chopping axe in my backpack. It’s very light for its size, so all you’re essentially carrying is the axe head. When you’re ready to set up camp, the weight was always worth it. Firewood duty becomes a breeze when you have a sharp beast like this in your kit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best of all, it’s an invaluable tool for splitting wood for the home fireplace. It’s easy to sharpen and is beefy enough to withstand a good amount of abuse, and still hold an edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My only gripe with this axe is its size - but that’s on me. Not an ideal backpacking axe, but it did the trick - especially for shorter stretches, and at-home splitting. I think my next purchase will be a smaller version of this very chopping axe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BPYFe5xjG1f/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A post shared by Max (@bakkenaction)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2017-01-17T18:56:50+00:00&quot;&gt;Jan 17, 2017 at 10:56am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2jxciya&quot;&gt;
    &lt;button class=&quot;btn--cta&quot;&gt;
        Buy it now
    &lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;11-my-custom-toolemergency-kit&quot;&gt;11. My Custom Tool/Emergency Kit&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My essentials are first-aid, fishing line and tackle, matches, rope, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2jAyxX2&quot;&gt;Swiss Army Knife&lt;/a&gt;, and my own version of the &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fieldandstream.com/photos/gallery/survival/food/2006/08/make-survival-kit-out-altoids-tin-and-two-more-life-saving-diy-#page-3&quot;&gt;Altoids Tin Survival Kit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BSBOfXEDuBM/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A post shared by Tips for SHTF (@offthegridguide)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2017-03-24T11:27:12+00:00&quot;&gt;Mar 24, 2017 at 4:27am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fieldandstream.com/photos/gallery/survival/food/2006/08/make-survival-kit-out-altoids-tin-and-two-more-life-saving-diy-#page-3&quot;&gt;
    &lt;button class=&quot;btn--cta&quot;&gt;
        Make your own
    &lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;12-8-x-10-blue-poly-tarp&quot;&gt;12. 8’ x 10’ Blue Poly Tarp&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This piece of kit is an absolute classic. Campers from all walks of life - from minimalists to glampers -  swear by this blue wonder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s incredibly affordable, light, packable and versatile. I’m sure these things save lives. I’m sure hardcore backpackers carry something that’s half its size and weight, but the sheer number of uses make this tarp a must-have for any casual camper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-pin-do=&quot;embedPin&quot; data-pin-width=&quot;large&quot; data-pin-terse=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.pinterest.com/pin/93942342211080408/&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2ihZx9E&quot;&gt;
    &lt;button class=&quot;btn--cta&quot;&gt;
        Buy it now
    &lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <media:content url="https://gohobo.co/assets/img/blog/whats-in-my-backpack-camping-edition.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpg" > </media:content>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://gohobo.co/journal/whats-in-my-backpack-camping-edition/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gohobo.co/journal/whats-in-my-backpack-camping-edition/</guid>
        
        <category>camping</category>
        
        <category>gear</category>
        
        
        <category>journal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Volunteer Jobs for Tax Free Nomad Income</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Wanna live somewhere wild and cool? Wanna hang a bit, then move on? Wanna make a living? Tax free? Volunteer in US national forests, parks, or other federal lands. Most only ask for a two-month minimum commitment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;make-tax-free-income-with-volunteer-work&quot;&gt;Make Tax-Free Income With Volunteer Work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vanholio’s making a tax-free income right now as a volunteer park host. It’s actually enough for me to live on, a bit over $500 per month. (Van life can be dang cheap – if you do it right.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The job’s in a US National Forest. And it’s Uncle Sam that pays the bills! (No, I ain’t telling you where. Go find your own honey hole!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most days, I do 2-3 hours of grunt work max. Then I just hang out and answer questions. It’s a beautiful spot, too. I mean, you can’t hardly buy real estate like that. Even if you’re a billionaire!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-i-get-as-a-park-host&quot;&gt;What I GET as a Park Host&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;$25 tax-free per diem ($540 per month)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Free RV site with hookups&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Free propane&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Free WiFi internet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Free use of government 4WD&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Free use of laundry facilities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Free snazzy uniform&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Free “America the Beautiful” park pass&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pride of doing good&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-i-do-as-park-host&quot;&gt;What I DO as Park Host&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clean bathrooms&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Haul trash&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mow and trim&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Answer questions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yell at kids to behave – BONUS!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hand out maps and brochures&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remind people to pay&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open and close the gates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;volunteer-jobs-besides-camp-hosting&quot;&gt;Volunteer Jobs Besides Camp Hosting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The national forests, national parks, and other federal agencies have more volunteer jobs than park hosts and camp hosts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maintenance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Repair backcountry trails&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plant trees&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Garden&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Staff information booths and visitor centers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Help out on archaeological digs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Got a volunteer service idea that isn’t posted at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.volunteer.gov/&quot;&gt;Volunteer.gov&lt;/a&gt;? Pitch it! Most agencies will consider letting you create your own job, so long as they see the need. Vanholio’s gonna propose cleaning up &lt;a href=&quot;https://freecampsites.net/dispersed-camping/&quot;&gt;dispersed campsites&lt;/a&gt; along the forest roads. Really, you should see the trash people leave behind!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-qualify-for-a-volunteer-job&quot;&gt;How to Qualify for a Volunteer Job&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a volunteer, your labor is cheap to free. So naturally, the feds don’t ask too many questions. But they gotta ask a few. Mainly, they need to make sure you’re not sketchy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Vanholio applied, he had to provide a resume, valid ID (driver’s license or passport), job application, and three references.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;can-non-citizens-get-volunteer-jobs&quot;&gt;Can Non-Citizens Get Volunteer Jobs?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Foreigners without work visas can volunteer, but they don’t make it worth your while. At least if you care about the benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Non-US citizens need to go through a rigmarole to get a special J-1 visa. It takes months of hoops, including a consulate interview. And after all that, you still won’t even give you so much as a free RV pad! It probably ain’t worth it unless you really, really wanna help out at Yellowstone or something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;find-paying-jobs-on-volunteergov&quot;&gt;Find Paying Jobs on Volunteer.gov&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check through the jobs on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.volunteer.gov/&quot;&gt;Volunteer.gov&lt;/a&gt;. You’ll notice that most only give you an RV site with hookups, if that. And maybe propane. But keep looking! Also contact the office that posted a job you like anyway. Maybe all the benefits aren’t listed. Don’t hurt to ask!
Find Unlisted Volunteer Jobs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got somewhere you want to volunteer at? Don’t see a position with benefits posted? Call the local field, park, or district office and talk to the volunteer coordinator. Maybe they got something that’s not posted yet. Maybe they’ll create a job just for you!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <media:content url="https://gohobo.co/assets/img/blog/volunteer-jobs-tax-free-income.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpg" > </media:content>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://gohobo.co/journal/volunteer-jobs-tax-free-nomad-income/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gohobo.co/journal/volunteer-jobs-tax-free-nomad-income/</guid>
        
        <category>budget travel</category>
        
        <category>volunteering</category>
        
        
        <category>journal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Collection of Street Art from Around the World - Porto, Portugal</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;porto-portugal&quot;&gt;Porto, Portugal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/porto-portugal1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A phonebooth painted with 3 birds wearing hats - stacked atop the other.&quot; title=&quot;Phonebooth painted with 3 birds - wearing hats - stacked atop the other.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/porto-portugal3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An image of a man (stuck an old door) holding a sac on the end of a stick.&quot; title=&quot;An image of a man (stuck an old door) holding a sac on the end of a stick.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/porto-portugal4@2x.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Two duo-tone giraffe heads, glowing with love.&quot; title=&quot;Two street-art style giraffe heads, glowing with love.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/porto-portugal5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An image of a psychedelic face, with the words 'Bye Porto'&quot; title=&quot;A street art image of a psychedelic face, with the words 'Bye Porto'&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/porto-portugal6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A balcony walkway attached to an abandoned building painted with colorful graffiti tags.&quot; title=&quot;A balcony walkway attached to an abandoned building painted with colorful graffiti tags.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/porto-portugal7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A large mural on the side of an old concrete building, of an elderly man holding out a palm.&quot; title=&quot;A large mural on the side of an old concrete building, of an elderly man holding out a palm.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/porto-portugal8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A brightly colored tree, painted as if it's growing out of the sidewalk and up a wall.&quot; title=&quot;Street art of a brightly colored tree, painted as if it's growing out of the sidewalk and up a wall.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/porto-portugal9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A human form sitting cross-legged - filled with a rainbow, and clearly marking several Chakras.&quot; title=&quot;A human form sitting cross-legged - filled with a rainbow, and clearly marking several Chakras.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/porto-portugal10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A cartoon-style mural, of several brightly colored animal characters and a zombie standing in a field.&quot; title=&quot;A cartoon-style mural, of several brightly colored animal characters and a zombie standing in a field.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/porto-portugal11.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A portrait of a dark-haired woman weeping, surrounded by flowers, painted on a wall in Porto, Portugal.&quot; title=&quot;A portrait of a dark-haired woman weeping, surrounded by flowers, painted on a wall in Porto, Portugal.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/porto-portugal12.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A painting of a blue furry creature with many eyes, and a pair of red sneakers - peeing on the ground.&quot; title=&quot;A painting of a blue furry creature with many eyes, and a pair of red sneakers - peeing on the ground.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/porto-portugal13.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A black and white mural of a small child wearing a hood putting a finger to their mouth.&quot; title=&quot;A black and white mural of a small child wearing a hood putting a finger to their mouth.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/porto-portugal14.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Two complementary murals on opposing walls, of two faces - one shaded and realistic, the other a deep blue and shaded with red lines.&quot; title=&quot;Two complementary murals on opposing walls, of two faces - one shaded and realistic, the other a deep blue and shaded with red lines.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/porto-portugal15.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A headshot of a woman with teal hair and sunglasses, painted on a wall in Porto, Portugal.&quot; title=&quot;A headshot of a woman with teal hair and sunglasses, painted on a wall in Porto, Portugal.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/porto-portugal16.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A cartoon cat wearing a sweater and a top hat - sitting in a bricked-up window.&quot; title=&quot;A cartoon cat wearing a sweater and a top hat - sitting in a bricked-up window.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/porto-portugal17.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A steampunk-style headshot of a woman wearing a toque, with half a skeletal face, and several piercings.&quot; title=&quot;A steampunk-style headshot of a woman wearing a toque, with half a skeletal face, and several piercings.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/porto-portugal19.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A cube in 3d space, filled with imagery of deep space.&quot; title=&quot;A cube in 3d space, filled with imagery of deep space.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/porto-portugal18.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A psychedelic painting of a woman wearing glasses holding a crystal ball with an octopus hand - with text that says 'Welcome to my trip'&quot; title=&quot;A psychedelic painting of a woman wearing glasses holding a crystal ball with an octopus hand - with text that says 'Welcome to my trip'&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/porto-portugal20.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A portrait of an orange alien, in the classes form.&quot; title=&quot;A portrait of an orange alien, in the classes form.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/porto-portugal21.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A line-drawing graphic of a of human legs - no torso - with a head wear the crotch should be.&quot; title=&quot;A line-drawing graphic of a of human legs - no torso - with a head wear the crotch should be.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/porto-portugal22.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fresh Prince style 'Runis Muki'&quot; title=&quot;Fresh Prince style 'Runis Muki'&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/porto-portugal23.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A nude clown walking up a hill, wiping makeup off its face. Painted on the side of a build - on a hill.&quot; title=&quot;A nude clown walking up a hill, wiping makeup off its face. Painted on the side of a build - on a hill.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/porto-portugal24.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An abstract graphic of a woman with a sun hat painted on a phone booth.&quot; title=&quot;An abstract graphic of a woman with a sun hat painted on a phone booth.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <media:content url="https://gohobo.co/assets/img/blog/street-art/porto-portugal4.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpg" > </media:content>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://gohobo.co/journal/street-art-around-the-world-port-portugal/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gohobo.co/journal/street-art-around-the-world-port-portugal/</guid>
        
        <category>street art</category>
        
        <category>backpacking</category>
        
        
        <category>journal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Collection of Street Art from Around the World - Southern Mexico</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;oaxaca-oaxaca-mexico&quot;&gt;Oaxaca, Oaxaca, Mexico&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/oaxaca-mexico1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Old woman with a skeletal hand painted on the side of a building, Oaxaca, Mexico&quot; title=&quot;Old woman with a skeletal hand painted on the side of a building in Oaxaca, Mexico&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/oaxaca-mexico2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A painted graphic of of a dancer with a face painted like a skeleton.&quot; title=&quot;A painted graphic of of a dancer with a face painted like a skeleton.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/oaxaca-mexico3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Street painting of Chewbacca eating a torta.&quot; title=&quot;Street painting of Chewbacca eating a torta.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/oaxaca-mexico4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Painting of a person wearing an indigenous mask.&quot; title=&quot;Painting of a person wearing an indigenous mask.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;oventique-chiapas-mexico&quot;&gt;Oventique, Chiapas, Mexico&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/oventique-mexico1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A mural tribute to Ernesto Che Guevara, Oventique, Mexico&quot; title=&quot;A mural tribute to Ernesto Che Guevara in Oventique, Mexico&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/oventique-mexico2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mural of multi-coloured maize, Oventique, Mexico&quot; title=&quot;Mural of multi-coloured maize in Oventique, Mexico&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/oventique-mexico3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wall painting of an aloe plant growing from the palm of a hand.&quot; title=&quot;Wall painting of an aloe plant growing from the palm of a hand.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;santa-cruz-xoxocotlan-oaxaca-mexico&quot;&gt;Santa Cruz Xoxocotlan, Oaxaca, Mexico&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/santa-cruz-xoxocotlan-mexico1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skeleton conquistador with a big mustache.&quot; title=&quot;Skeleton conquistador with a big mustache.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/santa-cruz-xoxocotlan-mexico3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An anthropomorphic orange tree, Santa Cruz Xoxocotlan, Mexico&quot; title=&quot;An anthropomorphic orange tree in Santa Cruz Xoxocotlan, Mexico&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/santa-cruz-xoxocotlan-mexico2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Street scene of skeletons with guns wearing pin-stripe suits, and a skeleton women smoking a cigarette.&quot; title=&quot;Street art scene of skeletons with guns wearing pin-stripe suits, and a skeleton women smoking a cigarette.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/santa-cruz-xoxocotlan-mexico4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A glowing octopus painted on a wall.&quot; title=&quot;A glowing octopus painted on a wall.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/santa-cruz-xoxocotlan-mexico5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skeletons drinking beer around a table painted on a wall.&quot; title=&quot;Skeletons drinking beer around a table painted on a wall.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;san-cristobal-chiapas-mexico&quot;&gt;San Cristobal, Chiapas, Mexico&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/san-cristobal-mexico1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;People in Mayan dress sitting in flying saucers and an alien holding a fetus, San Cristobal, Mexico&quot; title=&quot;People in Mayan dress sitting in flying saucers and an alien holding a fetus in San Cristobal, Mexico&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/san-cristobal-mexico2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Painting of a young boy dressed in green, holding a flower.&quot; title=&quot;Painting of a young boy dressed in green, holding a flower.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/san-cristobal-mexico3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A mural tribute to Zapata being stared at by a jaguar.&quot; title=&quot;A mural tribute to Zapata being stared at by a jaguar.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/san-cristobal-mexico4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A woman with butterflies in her eyes, painted on a wall.&quot; title=&quot;A woman with butterflies in her eyes, painted on a wall.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/san-cristobal-mexico5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A psychedelic painting of snakes.&quot; title=&quot;A psychedelic painting of snakes.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/san-cristobal-mexico6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Street art of a neon-purple armadillo with a sliced-up tail.&quot; title=&quot;Street art of a neon-purple armadillo with a sliced-up tail.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/san-cristobal-mexico7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A psychedelic green skull with 6 eyes, San Cristobal, Mexico&quot; title=&quot;A psychedelic green skull with 6 eyes in San Cristobal, Mexico&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/street-art/san-cristobal-mexico8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A mutant fish with many eyes holding a small blade, painted on a wall.&quot; title=&quot;A mutant fish with many eyes holding a small blade, painted on a wall.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <media:content url="https://gohobo.co/assets/img/blog/street-art/san-cristobal-mexico6.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpg" > </media:content>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://gohobo.co/journal/street-art-around-the-world-southern-mexico/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gohobo.co/journal/street-art-around-the-world-southern-mexico/</guid>
        
        <category>street art</category>
        
        <category>backpacking</category>
        
        
        <category>journal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Most Pointless Tourist Spots in the World</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever been somewhere on holiday and found yourself wondering, &lt;em&gt;why exactly did I ever think this would be a good idea&lt;/em&gt;? We’ve all done it – made plans to check out a popular or infamous locale, only to discover just how shoddy it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, let’s take a look at some such examples, as we explore some of the most pointless tourist spots in the world to visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-beijing-museum-of-tap-water--beijing&quot;&gt;1. Beijing Museum of Tap Water – Beijing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not even sure where to start with this one. Museums can sometimes run the risk of being a touch dull at the best of times; which is why we’re slightly concerned about the mental well-being of this building’s curator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Built on the site of the former Beijing City Water Supply, this museum &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thebeijinger.com/blog/2013/09/12/weird-weekend-beijing-tap-water-museum&quot; title=&quot;TheBeijinger.com&quot;&gt;takes you on a charted journey through the history of tap water&lt;/a&gt; in the Chinese capital. Why does this exist?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/pointless-tourist-spots_tap-water.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Water Tap by Jan Tik&quot; title=&quot;A pointless tourist destination - An outdoor water tap&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Image credit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jantik/&quot; title=&quot;Flickr.com&quot;&gt;Jan Tik&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-hollywood-walk-of-fame--hollywood&quot;&gt;2. Hollywood Walk of Fame – Hollywood&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Hollywood Walk of Fame was once a classy way of detailing some of the biggest names in the media business. These days, it’s so oversaturated with random nobodies the walk has lost all meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When all’s said and done, you’re doing nothing more than checking out a load of names written on the ground in what is said to be one of the tackier regions of Los Angeles. There are &lt;a href=&quot;www.manversusworld.com/5-reasons-why-hollywood-is-a-lame-tourist-destination/&quot; title=&quot;ManVersusWorld.com&quot;&gt;plenty of reasons why this locale stands out as a pretty shoddy destination&lt;/a&gt;, but the lack of anything to actually do here is one of the primary ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-mannekenpis--brussels&quot;&gt;3. MannekenPis – Brussels&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d love to tell you the title of this statue in Brussels is just an unfortunate coincidence in translation, but sadly it’s a very fair reflection of what you should expect to find. The MannekenPis is quite literally a little chap having a pee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such is the disappointment and absurdity of this pointless spot, many expert travellers have been left to wonder if they’re even in the right place when they arrive. We’re not sure why or how this ever became the national icon it is, but it’s definitely one you can afford to miss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/pointless-tourist-spots_mannekinpis.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MannekenPis Fountain by Nigel&quot; title=&quot;Pointless tourist destinations - Statue of a child peeing into the water&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Image credit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/nigel321/&quot; title=&quot;Flickr.com&quot;&gt;Nigel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-stonehenge--uk&quot;&gt;4. Stonehenge – UK&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This area of the UK is one which is definitely worth checking out if you have a strong historical interest in the Bronze Age. However, if you’re not someone studying this period of history, there’s very little else appealing about the spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a massive restriction on how close you can actually get to the monument itself, you don’t even have the joy of playing among the stones that past generations did. All in all, a trip to Stonehenge will see you walk around some old rocks in a massive circle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-burnside-fountain--massachusetts&quot;&gt;5. Burnside Fountain – Massachusetts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Concluding our list is one of the oddest things you’re ever likely to see in civilised society. The Burnside Fountain is – and I’m not kidding here – a bronze statue of a man seemingly straddling a turtle. He’s allegedly riding it, but I have my doubts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes this already questionable spot even more pointless is the fact this fountain is no longer operational. With no purpose and one of the oddest images we’ve ever seen in a public park, “Turtle Boy” as he’s been dubbed is definitely one of the most pointless attractions out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/pointless-tourist-spots_burnside-fountain.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Burnside Fountain by Tony Webster&quot; title=&quot;Pointless tourist spots - Statue of a guy riding a turtle.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Image credit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/diversey/&quot; title=&quot;Flickr.com&quot;&gt;Tony Webster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re next on holiday make sure you don’t waste your time at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.1cover.ca/secret-traveller/disappointing-tourist-attractions/&quot; title=&quot;1Cover.ca&quot;&gt;one of these pointless tourist attractions&lt;/a&gt;. Find something worthwhile to do with your time and give the spots we’ve covered today a miss.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <media:content url="https://gohobo.co/assets/img/blog/pointless-tourist-spots_burnside-fountain.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpg" > </media:content>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://gohobo.co/journal/pointless-tourist-spots/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gohobo.co/journal/pointless-tourist-spots/</guid>
        
        <category>contributed</category>
        
        <category>tourism</category>
        
        
        <category>journal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Peer-to-Peer Gear Trade</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-else-can-we-do-we-already-recycle&quot;&gt;What else can we do? We already recycle!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wanted to be a part of something bigger than yourself? To step away from what everyone is doing and do it just a little bit different? If you’d rather help out the little guy than the corporate giant and believe in a sharing economy, then this is worth a read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most outdoor adventurers regularly do their part for the planet. We recycle like crazy. Paper. Plastic. Glass. Metal. No problem. We might even literally collect waste (read compost) and stockpile it in our backyards. Solar power? Heck ya, that’s exiting! Electric cars? All praise Elon Musk (founder of Tesla)! However, with the exception of composting, this stuff becomes pretty high tech and costly. But there are also low-tech and low-cost ways for anyone to limit their eco-footprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;limit-waste&quot;&gt;Limit waste&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course this is an obvious one. Seasoned backpackers excel at this out of necessity, but why doesn’t this translate to everyday life? Like in the grocery store: why is there bread that is wrapped in plastic and then placed in another plastic bag? Or toilet paper that is individually wrapped in plastic, stacked in a pile of 24 and then wrapped in plastic again? If you are ready to step up your game, and your local market allows for this, try shopping with a goal of zero trash. Bring your own glass containers, weigh them in store and be on your merry shopping way. Oh, and ‘Limiting Waste 101’: don’t forget those reusable bags!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pack-it-in-pack-it-out&quot;&gt;Pack it in pack it out&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because it’s truly difficult (but apparently possible) to rid your life of waste completely, what really matters is that your waste actually ends up in the trash. Veer from the thought that, “it’s just one plastic cup” or “just one can”. Keep this in mind when you are prepping for a backpacking trip. Cliché but here it is: pack it in, pack it out. If you carried it in, then you have space to carry it out. Even your compostable food needs to be packed out; seeds can germinate and introduce new species to the area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think ahead and bring something to carry your garbage in so that it doesn’t leak all over your clothes. You can even bring an extra bag as you are sure to come across other people’s trash. Essentially: try to leave nothing but footprints. Stay on the trails and set up camp on existing campsites where applicable; otherwise find firm, dry ground with minimal vegetation. P.S. Don’t forget that garden trowel ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, but limiting waste and recycling the usuals is a given. But what about all that outdoor clothing, footwear and gear? Finding a place to recycle textiles can be difficult. Plus, &lt;em&gt;old gear&lt;/em&gt; often has life left to give when you decide to upgrade your equipment. Enter… &lt;strong&gt;Never Tracked Out Gear Trade&lt;/strong&gt;- an online solution for reducing outdoor gear waste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;recycle-your-gear&quot;&gt;Recycle your gear&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does it work? In two ways. First, not all communities have mastered the local buy and sell of outdoor gear. And sometimes that perfect buyer lives beyond the borders of your current city, making it tricky to exchange the goods securely. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nevertrackedout.ca/&quot; title=&quot;NeverTrackedOut.ca - Peer-to-peer outdoor gear trade&quot;&gt;Never Tracked Out&lt;/a&gt; connects communities across Canada with an online buy-and-sell that offers secure payment and shipping options. This means you don’t have to worry about being the first one to make a move, whether you are the buyer or the seller, because NTO guarantees the transaction’s success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what if you want to keep that 42L pack because &lt;em&gt;once in a while&lt;/em&gt; your 35L is not quite enough? NTO also created an online platform for you to &lt;em&gt;rent&lt;/em&gt; out your extra gear: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nevertrackedout.com/&quot; title=&quot;NeverTrackedOut.com&quot;&gt;peer to peer - across the globe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/peer-to-peer-gear-trade-outdoor-gear.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rent, buy, or sell outdoor gear like hiking boots, backpacks, tents, and much more.&quot; title=&quot;Hiking boots and a backpack set by the edge of a mountain lake.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When people travel, they often can’t bring all their gear with them. Your gear might be just the thing someone else needs to start their next adventure. Paddleboards, canoes, kayaks and tents will be sought after items this spring and summer. Or sometimes people just need an extra camp stove, cooler or dry bag to complete their gear repertoire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We currently have an owner that listed his rooftop cargo carrier for rent; talk about thinking &lt;em&gt;outside the box&lt;/em&gt;. With a &lt;strong&gt;peer to peer rental platform&lt;/strong&gt; we can make items like these more accessible and more affordable. It’s a platform that fosters the sharing economy, where gear owners can share their gear and their knowledge with gear renters. That doesn’t mean that you have to divulge the secrets of your favourite powder stash, perfect curl or secret trail, but you can recommend a good starting point keeping in mind what you would appreciate if you were borrowing gear from a local.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never Tracked Out Gear Trade was born out of the idea that gear sharing can have an even greater impact on the environment than it currently does. Sure it’s sometimes quick and easy to sell your gear on your local Facebook buy-and-sell or on mass markets like Kijiji, but how much value is there in that? Can it be done better?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a member of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.onepercentfortheplanet.org/&quot; title=&quot;One Percent for the Planet - All Together for our Planet&quot;&gt;1% For The Planet&lt;/a&gt;, we want your gear sharing to give back to the planet. NTO was built on values of helping others, buying local, recycling and giving back. We all love to adventure and we all love the land we play on, so let’s start protecting it together in a type of gear share movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe that a well-run gear share can help others get outside, put a little extra money in your pocket and reduce consumption. Why not share your extra gear, help out others and get to know neighbours or visitors from around the world. It’s about human connections, the experience and reducing our eco-footprint by sharing what might otherwise go to waste. If and when your gear does finally reach the end of its life, try to find a place that will properly recycle textiles. Contact us and we’ll be happy to help find a solution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <media:content url="https://gohobo.co/assets/img/blog/peer-to-peer-gear-trade_never-tracked-out-gear.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpg" > </media:content>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://gohobo.co/journal/peer-to-peer-gear-trade/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gohobo.co/journal/peer-to-peer-gear-trade/</guid>
        
        <category>outdoors</category>
        
        <category>peer-to-peer</category>
        
        
        <category>journal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Reasons to Rent an RV for your Next Vacation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you like vacations but loathe the travel method of flying? Do you want to enjoy the journey just as much as the destination? Are you thinking of embarking on an adventure that puts you in the Captain’s seat? Maybe renting an RV for your next vacation getaway is the answer you have been looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, travelers are more open about making a journey by black top instead of by air. Being able to have the control to stop and go as you choose. Pull over and try out one of those famous diners that you heard about from a TV show, or stop and see iconic landmarks that you have always wanted to see. Or, maybe it’s been a desire to take the back-roads and see what beautiful landscapes the country has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Renting an RV is like having your own vacation rental on wheels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to traveling by an RV, just pack up and go. Even if you don’t own an RV, finding a unit to rent has never been simpler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 5 reasons why you should consider renting an RV for your next road trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-family-time&quot;&gt;1. Family Time&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the heart of any family vacation, the end result is to create memories. Many travelers will recall the destination as the highlight, especially if you fly. But for those traveling in a motorhome, the road trip is the icing on the cake. Its two adventures in one; the journey and the destination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shoes come off, the passengers sink into the couches and chairs and everyone is riding in comfort. Legs are stretched and family members can feel relaxed. No one has to worry about elbow tucking or sitting awkward while sharing the back seat. No one needs to ask Dad to, “scoot the seat up” while Mom is figuring out creative ways to store the snacks inside the vehicle. Everyone has room and everyone is happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the family is happy, it’s easier to engage in conversations. The family feels like they started their vacation the moment they stepped inside the RV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a vacation rental on wheels, the journey is up to you. Take advantage of the freedom and discover new places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-life-changing&quot;&gt;2. Life Changing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traveling by road does a couple things. For starters, you see the world differently. As people, we grow acclimated to the lifestyle and culture of our city or town. Once on the road, we become exposed to a change of pace, seeing new places, people and lifestyles. Even if you are only driving within the same state, new places are new places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second best thing to happen on the road is personal interaction over technology. Whether its business related or personal preference, electronic devices have our undivided attention. Once inside the RV, electronic devices go off and everyone engages with one another. You’ll be surprised the things you learn about each other on the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-cost-savings&quot;&gt;3. Cost Savings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When compared to conventional traveling, renting an RV can save 30%-40% on your vacation when matched against driving your own vehicle, taking into account the money spent on dining and staying in hotel rooms. Of course, the destination and lifestyle will dictate costs, but being able to cook your own meals and stay where you like is where you make your savings. True, the fuel economy of any RV is nowhere near the mileage you would get from a car, but the savings from sleeping and dining in a RV helps offset the expenses you pay for fuel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-resorts&quot;&gt;4. Resorts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RV Resorts are a great way to recharge your batteries. These beautiful and relaxing locations can be found scattered throughout United States. Filled with amenities to make any traveler feel like a king, you’ll think you found a hidden gem when it comes to RV campsites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At an RV resort, soak up the sun while reading a good book next to a heated pool. Visit the clubhouse, watch some TV or enjoy a cocktail by the fire. Partake in the daily sponsored activities or attend a special event. There’s no reason to leave the resort, you can enjoy music, fine dining and other on-site attractions that will keep you entertained throughout the duration of your stay. Most even have an on-site store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RV resorts are great for all ages and can also be a valuable resourceful, especially if visiting a popular location with high amounts of traffic and tourists. For instance, if you haven’t been to Disneyland theme park in California, it’s hard to find a decent hotel that is close enough to walk, or offers a shuttle service and doesn’t break the bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the same with Las Vegas. Many of the suites in the Casinos are gorgeous, but they are also pricey. If you like to visit these places often and want to save on lodging, there are RV parks located near both areas and offer amazing amenities for your personal enjoyment at a fraction of the price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-glamping&quot;&gt;5. Glamping&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may be asking yourself, “What’s glamping?” Glamping means “glamorous camping.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the combination of camping and luxury. Having an RV allows campers to enjoy the great outdoors without sacrificing comfort and convenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Travelers can setup camp on the edge of their favorite river while sleeping on a queen sized pillow top bed, in a climate controlled mobile fortress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food and meals are easy to manage. Food stays cold and fresh by the built in refrigerator, where meals can be made in minutes thanks to the mobile kitchen. Use the on-board appliances to bake, boil, or even fry your dishes, just like you would at home. With an RV, cooking isn’t limited to a campfire - save that for the S’mores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another advantage of camping in a RV is having a bathroom at your disposal. This is especially useful at night. You don’t have to put on shoes and stumble around in the dark. Also, if you get dirty while camping, you can take a shower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, camping in an RV means that you can bring the things that mean most and make your experience memorable. For kids, it could be watching movies. For adults, it could be listening to music under the awning while sitting next to the campfire. Glamping is the perfect way for travelers who want to enjoy the outdoors, but still feel at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Renting an RV has many benefits and just like a hotel, they come in a variety of styles, prices and amenities. With so many choices out on the market, try a few different models until you find the recreation vehicle that not only fits your lifestyle and needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <media:content url="https://gohobo.co/assets/img/blog/5-reasons-rent-rv-vacation.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpg" > </media:content>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://gohobo.co/journal/5-reasons-to-rent-rv-next-vacation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gohobo.co/journal/5-reasons-to-rent-rv-next-vacation/</guid>
        
        <category>roadtrip</category>
        
        <category>transportation</category>
        
        
        <category>journal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hitchhiking on Airplanes with Wingly</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;flight-sharing&quot;&gt;Flight Sharing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world has never been as connected as it is today, the planet itself feels smaller. It was only a matter of time before the sharing economy took to the skies, and it has successfully taken off with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wingly.io/&quot; title=&quot;Wingly.io&quot;&gt;Wingly&lt;/a&gt;. Alternative air travellers are poking around flight sharing platforms, and are taking a few steps away from traditional booking websites. After all, why queue at the airport when you can catch a private flight for the price of a train ticket?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/hitchhiking-on-airplanes-flyover.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A view of a city from a small plane - Wingly&quot; title=&quot;A view of a city from a small plane - Wingly&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;aviation-story&quot;&gt;Aviation story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flying is the oldest human dream, and that is not surprising at all. Sadly, the concept of flying has been over-commercialized these past few decades, draining the experience of its awe and wonder. We have arrived at a point where flying is similar to taking the bus. Nonetheless, one activity has preserved its passion for flight; light aviation. The activity of flying light aircraft reminds us why the Wright brothers took to the skies again after every failed attempt. It is a fascinating endeavor, an experience full of admiration and wonderment. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flight_sharing&quot; title=&quot;Flight Sharing - Wikipedia.org&quot;&gt;Flight sharing&lt;/a&gt; platforms aim to bring that excitement into everyone’s reach and offers everyone a chance to re-discover the charm of flight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;click-click-and-away&quot;&gt;Click, Click, and Away&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boarding a light plane is a few clicks away, just think of all the places you can go! Two types of flight are immediately available; sightseeing flights, and transportation flights. The former are discovery flights, where departure and arrival are at the same location, it is the impeccable opportunity to enter an exceptional layer of the atmosphere, and admire landscapes from an altitude experienced by few. The latter are transit flights, getting you from point A to point B, where these points aren’t necessarily airports, but airfields. Taking the route less travelled is sometimes the case, with unusual destinations for city escapes constituting part of the adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/hitchhiking-on-airplanes-small-plane-flight-sharing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A couple of pilots preparing for a flight-share - Wingly&quot; title=&quot;A couple of pilots preparing for a flight-share - Wingly&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;peer-to-peer-operations&quot;&gt;Peer to Peer Operations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The secret recipe behind these platforms resides in sharing the thrill of the journey, as well as it’s costs. Indeed, it is the perfect virtual space for flying enthusiasts and pilots to interact. Your account, as either passenger or pilot, is your ticket to the skies. Passengers can locate pilots near them using an interactive map and request flights by dropping a message or accept one of the numerous suggestions readily available. A refreshed sense of wanderlust accompanies this digital mode of transportation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/hitchhiking-on-airplanes-underwing-view-flight-share.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The view from between the wings - Wingly&quot; title=&quot;The view from between the wings - Wingly&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;convenience-customized&quot;&gt;Convenience Customized&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20160711-the-hacks-that-make-air-travel-less-painful&quot; title=&quot;Air Travel Hacks - BBC Future&quot;&gt;Hacking air travel&lt;/a&gt; by sharing flights not only takes you off the beaten path, but it also comes with unprecedented flexibility. If the timing doesn’t suit you, for example, you can agree with the pilot on a different time - knowledge of the aeronautical alphabet is not mandatory! The best part of flight sharing is undoubtedly your seat. Forget about aisle and window seats, your pilot has found his co-pilot in you. Part of the adventure is listening in on his live chit-chat with the control tower and tracking his airborne movements around landmarks or coastlines on a map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/hitchhiking-on-airplanes-matterhorn.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Matterhorn from a plane-share - Wingly&quot; title=&quot;The Matterhorn from a plane-share&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pilots--co-pilots&quot;&gt;Pilots &amp;amp; Co-Pilots&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By all means, go ahead and find a pilot near you. Light aviation is probably the coolest gizmo to enter the cybernetic world recently, and it’s time to try it out. Diversify your life experiences with an uncommon trip! Fly smarter by skipping unending terminals, take a round-trip discovery flight through the mountains, or get a new perspective on the setting sun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;connect-with-wingly&quot;&gt;Connect with Wingly&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instagram: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/flywingly/&quot;&gt;@flywingly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/flywingly/&quot;&gt;FlyWingly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Wingly_UK&quot;&gt;@wingly_uk &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <media:content url="https://gohobo.co/assets/img/blog/hitchhiking-on-airplanes-wingly.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpg" > </media:content>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://gohobo.co/journal/hitchhiking-on-airplanes-wingly/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gohobo.co/journal/hitchhiking-on-airplanes-wingly/</guid>
        
        <category>alternative travel</category>
        
        <category>transportation</category>
        
        
        <category>journal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Alternative Adventure People You Should Know</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This time around I wanted to throw a shout-out to some lesser-known alternative adventure folk who really have a lot to offer. I’ve compiled a list of GoHobo’s favourite go-tos when it comes to adventure inspiration. Whether you’re living in a van down by the river, flying across the ocean to explore new cultures, or hiking in your own backyard; these people will surely scratch your itchy feet (that’s a real expression, I swear).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-go-the-travel-podcast&quot;&gt;1. Go The Travel Podcast&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unique stories of adventure, travel, and culture from around the globe. Alex and Laura have a fascinating and journalistic approach to alternative travel. Follow along as they explore far beyond regular tourism, and into the heart of adventure.   &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stitcher.com/podcast/go-the-travel-podcast/go-the-podcast&quot;&gt;Listen to the podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:34.81481481481482% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BODFgxujzO5/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A photo posted by Go The Travel Podcast (@gothetravelpodcast)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2016-12-15T18:41:39+00:00&quot;&gt;Dec 15, 2016 at 10:41am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-vanholio&quot;&gt;2. Vanholio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A van-dwelling realist and a modern philosopher, sharing real van life experiences across the USA. Well spoken, and well written, Vanholio keeps it real and amusing with weekly manifests from his on-the-road adventures.
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vanholio.com/&quot;&gt;Read the manifesto at Vanholio.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:28.14814814814815% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BY6ZQKfgOCf/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A post shared by Vanholio! (@vanholio69)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2017-09-11T19:26:19+00:00&quot;&gt;Sep 11, 2017 at 12:26pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-indie-voyager&quot;&gt;3. Indie Voyager&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indie Voyager is an alternative travel guru, living on the wild side of European travel. Frequenting music festivals as a photographer, shooting street art, and hitchhiking around the continent. The guy knows how to get around. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.indievoyager.com/&quot;&gt;Read some indie travel tips at IndieVoyager.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BKlc67WBMXu/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A photo posted by Indie Voyager (@indievoyager)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2016-09-20T16:54:48+00:00&quot;&gt;Sep 20, 2016 at 9:54am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-by-the-way&quot;&gt;4. By The Way&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomás and Viriato are two adrenaline junkies living life to the fullest - and proving that a life of adventure doesn’t really cost much. They live by the mantra, &lt;em&gt;we weren’t born to pay bills and die&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/btw.project/&quot;&gt;See their adventures on Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:37.5% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BM9wEwKh7oi/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A post shared by By the way (@btw.project)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2016-11-18T20:26:44+00:00&quot;&gt;Nov 18, 2016 at 12:26pm PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-dharma-on-wheels&quot;&gt;5. Dharma On Wheels&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bus-dwelling family, with hearts full of wanderlust. Currently posted in Alberta, Canada where they are building out their #skoolie.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/our.dharma.tribe/&quot;&gt;Follow their progress on Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:41.388888888888886% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BZjju_1gcX1/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A post shared by David, Melanie &amp;amp; Alice (@our.dharma.tribe)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2017-09-27T19:06:46+00:00&quot;&gt;Sep 27, 2017 at 12:06pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;6-venture&quot;&gt;6. +Venture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A youthful crew of true weekend warriors with loads of positive energy, and a true appreciation of nature.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/addventure_co/&quot;&gt;View their adventures on Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:33.3333333333% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BPEXexYhjtI/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A photo posted by +Venture Co. (@addventure_co)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2017-01-10T03:09:18+00:00&quot;&gt;Jan 9, 2017 at 7:09pm PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;7-vancrush&quot;&gt;7. Van.Crush&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day, #VanGrrrl lights up my Instagram feed with an epic curation of beautiful, glorious van-living.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/van.crush/&quot;&gt;Get van-life inspired on Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:48.0952380952% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BPY6wmYDFkP/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A photo posted by Elizabeth aka @van_grrrl (@van.crush)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2017-01-18T02:42:23+00:00&quot;&gt;Jan 17, 2017 at 6:42pm PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;8-we-are-wildness&quot;&gt;8. We Are Wildness&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A community with a mission: helping people rewild their lives by re-connecting with the natural world, through courses, meetups and inspiration. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://wearewildness.com/&quot;&gt;Re-Wild your life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BZ7wEg1gVUm/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A post shared by We Are Wildness (@wearewildness)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2017-10-07T04:36:20+00:00&quot;&gt;Oct 6, 2017 at 9:36pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <media:content url="https://gohobo.co/assets/img/blog/alternative-adventure-people.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpg" > </media:content>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://gohobo.co/journal/alternative-adventure-people-you-should-know/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gohobo.co/journal/alternative-adventure-people-you-should-know/</guid>
        
        <category>adventure</category>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        
        <category>journal</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
